<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Codetracer</title>
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://yoursite.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-09-05T04:31:05.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://yoursite.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Zhengjie Wang</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CoolDown 经济学人阅读(31) - Fear of finance</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2017/09/05/fear-of-finance/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2017/09/05/fear-of-finance/</id>
    <published>2017-09-05T04:30:15.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-09-05T04:31:05.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Fear-of-finance"><a href="#Fear-of-finance" class="headerlink" title="Fear of finance"></a>Fear of finance</h1><p>文章选自2017/8/26的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>导读: 如何平衡金融稳定性与经济增长的关系， 是各国央行面临的挑战。 并且各国情况不尽相同</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>金融恐惧</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Financial stability is a growing concern of central banks. Only some should be worried</p>
</blockquote>
<p>金融稳定性是一个中央银行越来越关切的问题。 但只有一些问题应该被担心</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>financial stability</strong>:金融稳定</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>CENTRAL bankers have gathered at their annual shindig in Jackson Hole, Wyoming, for the past ten years with only one thing on their minds: the health of the global economy. This year’s gathering is different. The bankers’ preoccupations are changing, from recovery to financial stability.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>央行行长们已经在Jackson Hole, Wyoming的年度聚会上碰头，在过去十年中，只有一件事情萦绕他们心头:全球经济的健康</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>shindig(n.)</strong>: 狂欢聚会</li>
<li><strong>preoccupation(n.)</strong>: 长期专注的事<br>e.g. have a preoccupation with 专注于某事</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Oddly, rising concern about the risks of financial excess is good news. It reflects the arrival of the first synchronised global economic upswing since 2010. GDP growth in the quarter ending in June was the most rapid since then, according to JPMorgan Chase, thanks to stronger-than-expected activity in China, Japan and Europe (Britain was a notable exception). Any relief, however, is mixed with anxiety that the excesses which led to the crisis of 2007-08 are again pervasive.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>不断加重的对金融过度的风险的担心意外地成为了好消息。这反映出自2010年以来， 第一次同步化的全球金融改善的到来</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>financial excess</strong>: 金融过度</li>
<li><strong>upswing(n.)</strong>: 改善</li>
<li><strong>pervasive(adj.)</strong>: 弥漫的</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Policymakers have helped support the economy over the past decade. But by keeping interest rates low, they have also spurred investors to take extra risks in search of larger returns. The American stockmarket is on a cyclically adjusted price-earnings ratio of 30—a level surpassed only in 1929 and the late 1990s. Investors are rushing to buy government debt from risky countries. Argentina has defaulted on its debts six times in the past century, but still easily found buyers for a 100-year bond in June. Earlier this month buyers snapped up Iraq’s first independent bond issue for more than a decade.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>政策制定者已经在过去的十年中给予经济支持。 但通过保持低利率， 他们能刺激投资者冒额外的风险谋求更大的利益</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>spur investors to do</strong>:激励投资者做…<br>e.g. cut interest rates to spur demand 降低利率以刺激需求</li>
<li><strong>in search of</strong>: 寻求，搜索</li>
<li><strong>price-earnings ratio</strong>: 股票收益率</li>
<li><strong>government debt</strong>: 国债</li>
<li><strong>snap up</strong>: 抢购<br>e.g. The tickets were snapped up. 票被抢购一空</li>
<li><strong>bond issue</strong>: 债券发行</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>The tension between growth and stability is most obvious in China. The IMF this month simultaneously raised its growth forecasts and warned that the country was gorging itself on debt, which jumped from 150% of GDP in 2007 to 280% in 2016. Since the start of this year, the People’s Bank of China has restricted the supply of short-term liquidity to banks. Regulators have also ordered them to account for loans hidden off their balance-sheets. So far, so good: funding costs have risen and overall credit growth has slowed even as nominal growth has rebounded. But the economy has recently started to lose momentum. Will China continue efforts to constrain credit even when growth dips below official targets? The fear is that it will revert to type and let credit surge again.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>增长和稳定的紧张关系在中国最明显。 国际货币基金组织本月持续提出增长预测并且警告这个国家正在被债务吞噬， 从2007年150%的GDP到2016年280%的GDP</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>IMF(n.)</strong>: 国际货币基金组织</li>
<li><strong>gorge(v.)</strong>: 狼吞虎咽</li>
<li><strong>short-term liquidity</strong>: 资产的短期流动性</li>
<li><strong>account for</strong>: 解释…的原因</li>
<li><strong>balance-sheets</strong>: 资产负债表</li>
<li><strong>lose momentum</strong>: 失去动力</li>
<li><strong>dip(n.)</strong>: 下降</li>
<li><strong>surge(v.)</strong>: 上涨</li>
<li><strong>nominal growth</strong>: 名义上的增长</li>
<li><strong>lose momentum</strong>: 势头减弱</li>
<li><strong>revert to type</strong>: 恢复原状</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Concerns about financial fragility are of a very different kind in Europe, where a recovery is gaining strength. Since December, when the European Central Bank lowered its target for asset purchases, to €60bn ($70bn) a month, there has been speculation that the ECB’s programme of quantitative easing (QE, the creation of money to buy assets) must wind down soon. But the bank is nervous about a repeat of the “taper tantrum” of 2013, when markets were spooked by signals from the Fed that it would be stopping QE. A hurried withdrawal of QE might cause a sudden rise in bond yields as bubbly assets are repriced. That could hurt countries, such as Italy, with big public-debt burdens.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>对于金融脆弱性的担心是与欧洲的完全不同的， 在那里复苏正的趋势在变强。 自从十二月以来， 欧洲央行降低了不动产购买的指标， 到600亿一个月， 有预测指出欧洲央行的量化宽松计划也一定会放慢下来</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>asset purchase</strong>:资产收购</li>
<li><strong>quantitative easing</strong>: 量化宽松</li>
<li><strong>wind down</strong>: 平静下来</li>
<li><strong>taper tantrum</strong>: 缩减恐慌</li>
<li><strong>bond yield</strong>: 公债利息</li>
<li><strong>public debt</strong>: 公债</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>The Federal Reserve sits somewhere between China and Europe. The American economy has been expanding for years; only twice in its history has it grown for more consecutive quarters. Its financial system looks robust. But here, too, queasiness about share prices and the lengths to which investors will go to buy bonds with decent yields has crept into the Fed’s deliberations. As the crisis of 2007-08 fades from memory, the Fed is worrying about the efforts of the Trump administration to loosen the shackles that bind the banks. Stanley Fischer, its vice-chairman, has opposed proposals from the Treasury that “stress tests” of big banks should be softer.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>联邦储备银行出于中国和欧洲之间的某个位置。 美国经济已经持续增长了若干年； 在历史上只有两次持续增长了多个季度。美国的金融系统看似健壮。但是， 对于股价以及投资者持股周期的担忧已经在联邦储备银行的审议过程中蔓延</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Federal Reserve</strong>: 联邦储备银行</li>
<li><strong>queasiness(n.)</strong>: 不安</li>
<li><strong>creep into</strong>: 在…中蔓延</li>
<li><strong>deliberation(n.)</strong>: 审议过程</li>
<li><strong>fade from memory</strong>: 从记忆中消逝</li>
<li><strong>loosen the shackles</strong>: 解除束缚</li>
<li><strong>opposed proposals</strong>: 截然不同的提议</li>
<li><strong>the Treasury</strong>: 财政部</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Alarm bells<br>It is right that central banks should be vigilant about threats to financial stability. But the Fed should not yet put concerns about risk-taking above the immediate demands of the economy. American banks are well-capitalised; and there is a decent case for simplifying some post-crisis regulations, particularly those that bind America’s smaller lenders. As for the euro zone, its recovery is still recent and continues to need support; the ECB should not be withdrawing stimulus abruptly in any case. For China the real test lies ahead, perhaps as early as next year. Tensions between growth and stability will become more acute as time goes on. But as the central bankers descend on Wyoming, it is too soon for them to stop worrying about the health of the world economy.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>中央银行对针对金融稳定性的威胁保持警惕是正确的。 但是联邦银行还没有将对风险的担忧放到经济的当前需求之上</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>be vigilant about</strong>:对…保持警惕</li>
<li><strong>risk-taking(n.)</strong>: 冒险</li>
<li><strong>well-capitalised(n.)</strong>: 资本雄厚</li>
<li><strong>post-crisis regulation</strong>: 危机后管理</li>
<li><strong>stimulus(n.)</strong>: 刺激</li>
<li><strong>abruptly(adv.)</strong>: 突然地</li>
<li><strong>tension(n.)</strong>: 紧张关系</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h1 id=&quot;Fear-of-finance&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Fear-of-finance&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Fear of finance&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Fear of finance&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;文章选自2017/8/26的The 
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="English Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CoolDown 经济学人阅读(30) -  The right treatment</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2017/09/02/the-right-treatment/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2017/09/02/the-right-treatment/</id>
    <published>2017-09-01T23:57:09.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-09-01T23:57:56.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="The-right-treatment"><a href="#The-right-treatment" class="headerlink" title="The right treatment"></a>The right treatment</h1><p>文章选自2017/8/26的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>导读: 发展中国家的医疗系统逐年进步， 但是对于初等医疗水平依然很低。 作者讨论了初等医疗对于治疗慢性病， 提供快速及时的医疗咨询的重要意义，并给出了典范</p>
</blockquote>
<p>正确的医疗</p>
<blockquote>
<p>How developing countries should improve primary health care</p>
</blockquote>
<p>发展中国家应该如何提高初等医保水平</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>primary health care</strong>: 初级医保</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>IN POOR countries people are living longer and healthier lives than ever. Since 2000 child mortality has fallen by almost half. The rate of new HIV/AIDS infections has dropped by 40%. About 7m deaths from malaria have been prevented.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>在贫困国家人们比以往更加长寿和健康。 自从2008年以来，儿童死亡率已经降低了大约一半</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>child mortality</strong>: 儿童死亡率</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Yet there is much more to be done. By one measure, the World Health Organisation reckons about 400m people still have no access to primary care—the basic form of medicine that should be at the forefront of any well-run health system. The real figure is probably much higher. And even for those fortunate enough to see a general practitioner, or more usually a semi-trained medic or quack, treatment is often dire.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>然而还有更多需要做。 据统计， 世界卫生组织认为大约4千万人仍然没有初级医疗保障–一种在健全的医疗系统中最基础，最重要的医疗形式</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>by one measure</strong>: 据统计</li>
<li><strong>at the forefront of</strong>: 处于…最重要的位置</li>
<li><strong>well-run health system</strong>: 运行良好的医疗系统</li>
<li><strong>general practitioner</strong>: 全科医生</li>
<li><strong>semi-trained medic</strong>: 培训中的医科学生</li>
<li><strong>quack(n.)</strong>: 冒牌医生</li>
<li><strong>dire(adj.)</strong>: 急迫的<br>e.g. be in dire straits  陷入极度困境</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>The poor state of primary care will matter even more as the burden of disease in poor countries comes to resemble that in rich ones, shifting from infectious diseases to chronic conditions (see page 49). By 2020 non-communicable diseases will account for about 70% of deaths in developing countries. But the majority of people with high blood pressure, diabetes or depression do not get effective treatment—and may not even know they have a problem. They deserve better.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>贫穷国家的基础医疗将更加重要随着在贫穷国家的疾病负担与富裕国家一样，从流行病转变到慢性病</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>come to resemble</strong>: 就像</li>
<li><strong>infectious disease</strong>: 传染病</li>
<li><strong>chronic disease</strong>: 慢性病</li>
<li><strong>non-communicable disease</strong>: 慢性非传染性疾病</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Primary health care is not flashy, but it works. It is the central nervous system of a country’s medical services—monitoring the general health of communities, treating chronic conditions and providing day-to-day relief. It can ensure that an infectious disease does not become an epidemic. Before the Ebola outbreak of 2014, nearly half of Liberians could not afford primary care and the deadly virus spread quickly. In parts of west Africa with better primary care, it was more easily contained.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>初等医疗保障并非华而不实的， 它确实有效。 它是这个国家的医疗系统的中枢神经系统–监控着社区健康状况， 治疗慢性疾病和提供日常的救助</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>flashy(adj.)</strong>: 华而不实的</li>
<li><strong>central nervous system</strong>: 中枢神经系统</li>
<li><strong>chronic condition</strong>: 慢性疾病</li>
<li><strong>day-to-day</strong>: 日常的，每天的</li>
<li><strong>epidemic(n.)</strong>: 传染病</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Neglect of primary care is often the unintended result of good intentions. International aid-givers have concentrated much of their effort on cutting the rates of individual infectious diseases, partly because success at treating them is easier to measure. Governments in many developing countries, meanwhile, have ploughed scarce money into visible and expensive hospitals in big cities. Between 2002 and 2013 the number of larger hospitals in China nearly doubled, whereas the tally of primary-care providers shrank by 6%. China now has more hospital beds per person than America.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>对于初等医疗的忽略通常是良好规划导致的无意的结果。 国际救助者已经提供了很多努力用于降低个人传染病率， 部分是因为传染病的治疗更好测量</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>unintended result</strong>: 非计划中结果</li>
<li><strong>aid-giver(n.)</strong>: 救助者</li>
<li><strong>plough scarce money into</strong>:将紧缺的资金投入到…</li>
<li><strong>the tally of</strong>:账目</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Such lopsidedness is wasteful. Primary care can deal with the vast majority of medical consultations. Expanding primary care tends to bring marked improvements. Brazil’s “Family Health Programme”, which costs barely $50 a person and covers roughly half the population, has cut infant mortality and needless hospitalisation. Rwanda, Sri Lanka and Thailand have had similar success. Costa Rica spends far less than the global average on health, but has the highest life expectancy in the Americas after Canada and Chile, thanks to its impressive primary care.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>这样的不均衡是一种浪费。 初等医疗可以应对大量主要的医疗咨询。 扩大初等医疗可以带来更显著的提升</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>lopsidedness(n.)</strong>: 不匀称, 不均衡</li>
<li><strong>medical consultation</strong>: 医疗咨询</li>
<li><strong>marked improvements</strong>: 显著的改善</li>
<li><strong>cut infant mortality</strong>: 削减了婴儿死亡率</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>There are plenty of good examples to follow. The first step should be to train those already providing care, who are often private practitioners, ranging from drug dispensers to dubious healers. Some medical bodies would like to see care-providers without formal medical qualifications banned, but the evidence is that even short training courses can greatly improve their diagnoses. In South Africa a scheme called the Practical Approach to Care Kit (PACK) uses checklists to train health workers without medical degrees to diagnose 40 common symptoms and treat 20 chronic conditions.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>这里有很多好的例子。 第一步应当训练那些已经能提供医疗的人，这些人通常是私人医师， 从药剂师到不可靠的医师</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>dubious healer</strong>: 不可靠的医师</li>
<li><strong>drug dispenser</strong>: 药剂师</li>
<li><strong>improve their diagnoses</strong>: 提升诊断水平</li>
<li><strong>common symptoms</strong>: 常见症状</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>A second step is to make better use of technology. In Delhi’s 158 mohalla (community) clinics, the first of which opened in 2015, a testing-kit costing $640 can run 33 common medical tests. Rwanda is trying out a telemedicine scheme to make it easier for patients in rural areas to speak to a doctor. DHIS 2, a free, open-source system for collecting and sharing health data, is used in 47 countries.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>第二步就是确保科技得到更好地利用技术。 在德黒的158家诊所，正试用价值640美元的可用33次的检测套装</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>testing-kit</strong>: 检测套装</li>
<li><strong>try out</strong>: 试验</li>
<li><strong>telemedicine scheme</strong>: 远程诊断计划</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>A third important change is to design better incentives. Even when clinicians know how to deal with patients properly, they may not do so. Sometimes pressure from patients leads them to overprescribe antibiotics. The problem is made worse when doctors profit from the drugs they prescribe or the tests they order. Better to follow Rwanda, where health workers are rewarded for following clinical guidelines, not for the prescriptions they issue.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>有一个重要变化是设计更好的动机。尽管临床医生可用更好地处理病人的问题， 但是他们可能不会那么做</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>overprescribe(v.)</strong>: 过量开药</li>
<li><strong>antibiotics(n.)</strong>: 抗生素</li>
<li><strong>clinical guidelines</strong>: 临床指导</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Reading the vital signs<br>In much of the rich world, ageing populations and new technology are leading policymakers to rethink their health services. Many have belatedly realised that, for chronic conditions, there are better and cheaper alternatives to hospitals. Poorer countries have a chance to anticipate these changes. They should seize it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>在丰富的世界上， 老龄化的人口和新科技正引导决策之重新思考他们的医疗服务</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>vital(adj.)</strong>: 极其重要的</li>
<li><strong>anticipate these changes</strong>: 未雨绸缪</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h1 id=&quot;The-right-treatment&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#The-right-treatment&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;The right treatment&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The right treatment&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;文章
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="English Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CoolDown 经济学人阅读(29) -  Assembly required</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2017/08/27/assembly-required/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2017/08/27/assembly-required/</id>
    <published>2017-08-27T10:51:25.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-27T10:52:24.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Assembly-required"><a href="#Assembly-required" class="headerlink" title="Assembly required"></a>Assembly required</h1><p>文章选自2017/8/19的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流</p>
<blockquote>
<p>导读： 最近，宜家在塞尔维亚开设了第一家店， 一定程度上预示着这个国家的变革再次推延。</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>急需重建</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Sweden’s favourite shop reaches Belgrade</p>
</blockquote>
<p>瑞典最受欢迎的商店入驻贝尔格莱德(塞尔维亚首都)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>EUROPEAN integration takes different forms. For governments like Serbia’s it means struggling with thousands of instructions from the EU on how to build a modern state. Yet for thousands of ordinary Serbs, since IKEA opened in Belgrade on August 10th, it means spending the weekend like millions of other EU citizens: buying furniture from the Swedish megastore and struggling with the instructions on how to put it together.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>欧洲一体化以各种不同的形式进行着。对于像塞尔维亚一样的政府意味着同来自欧盟的上千条如何建造一个现代国家的教导做抗争。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If it had been anywhere else in Europe, the opening of the 400th IKEA store would hardly have been news, let alone an occasion for national soul-searching led by Serbia’s president, Aleksandar Vucic. In a newspaper article he penned an ode of praise for IKEA and Ingvar Kamprad, its founder. In his youth, wrote the president, Mr Kamprad had been a member of a wartime Swedish fascist party, but he had redeemed himself. No one in the Balkans needed to scratch their head and wonder what Mr Vucic was alluding to here. The president spent 16 years as a leading member of an extreme nationalist party whose men were infamous for murdering and looting their way across Bosnia and Croatia.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>如果它已经遍布欧洲， 那么第400家宜家的落成就不能算作新闻， 抛开由塞尔维亚总统，Aleksandar Vucic，发起的寻找国魂事件</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>let alone</strong>:别管</li>
<li><strong>occasion(n.)</strong>: 理由, 时机</li>
<li><strong>pen an ode of</strong>: 对…称颂</li>
<li><strong>allude to</strong>: 间接提到， 影射</li>
<li><strong>be infamous for</strong>: 因…而臭名昭著</li>
<li><strong>loot(v.)</strong>: 抢劫，洗劫</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Mr Vucic says he no longer believes in the ideas that motivated him then. He says his aim is to create a modern Serbia, but that the problem is that Serbs are lazy and constantly waiting for someone to tell them what to do. Mr Vucic has often talked of his admiration for northern Europeans and their Protestant work ethic. “Wouldn’t it be great”, mocked Dejan Anastasijevic, a columnist, “if Serbia could simply be disassembled, repaired, packed into a flat box and delivered to the president.” Or even better, have Serbs “replaced by Scandinavians”.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Vucic随即称他不再相信那些激励他的观念。 他说他意在创建一个现代的塞尔维亚， 但是问题是塞尔维亚人很懒并且始终在等待别人告诉他们应该怎么做</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Protestant(adj.)</strong>: 新教的</li>
<li><strong>columnist(n.)</strong>: 专栏作家</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>IKEA in Belgrade is a story rich in symbol. The firm opened a small outlet in 1991, only to close a year later as Yugoslavia collapsed. Its return is a tale of the country’s delayed transition. Slobodan Milosevic, Serbia’s wartime leader, fell 17 years ago. So why did it take so long? In 2008 when the country was led by the pro-European Boris Tadic, an attempt by IKEA to return was thwarted by bureaucracy and corruption. Many liberal Serbs hate Mr Vucic for his authoritarianism and cronyism: the fact that a symbol of European normality has reopened on his watch is a bitter pill for them to swallow.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>在贝尔格莱德的宜家是一个充满象征意义的报道。 这家公司在1991年开设了一家小门店， 仅仅在南斯拉夫解体一年之前。它的归来印证了国家延迟的变革的流言。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>outlet(n.)</strong>: 市场，商店</li>
<li><strong>be thwarted</strong>: 被阻挠</li>
<li><strong>authoritarianism(n.)</strong>: 专制主义</li>
<li><strong>cronyism(n.)</strong>: 任人唯亲</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h1 id=&quot;Assembly-required&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Assembly-required&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Assembly required&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Assembly required&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;文章选自2017/8
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="English Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CoolDown 经济学人阅读(28) - Double trouble</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2017/08/26/double-trouble/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2017/08/26/double-trouble/</id>
    <published>2017-08-25T16:16:36.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-25T16:17:15.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Double-trouble"><a href="#Double-trouble" class="headerlink" title="Double trouble"></a>Double trouble</h1><p>文章选自2017/8/19的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流</p>
<blockquote>
<p>导读: 澳大利亚是一个移民国家， 政府机关的要职严格限定必须由本国公民担当，并且该人不能有双重国籍。 但是现在，由于审核不严，出现了一些列问题</p>
<p>A row over who is eligible for parliament rattles the government</p>
</blockquote>
<p>一个关于谁有资格在议会任职的争吵令澳洲政府担心不已</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>a row over</strong>: 一次关于…的争吵</li>
<li><strong>be eligible for</strong>: 有资格做…</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>WHEN two Australian Greens senators left parliament last month after learning that they were dual citizens, and thus in breach of the constitution, Malcolm Turnbull, the prime minister, condemned their “incredible sloppiness”. But on August 14th Barnaby Joyce, the deputy prime minister, revealed that he, too, was a citizen of two countries: Australia and New Zea- land. His confession sparked a rare dip- lomatic row between the two countries. It also casts doubt on the survival of Mr Turnbull’s government, which clings to power with a majority of one.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>两个澳大利亚绿党议员上个月被查出是双重国籍，因而违宪而离开了议会。 在那时， 澳洲总理， Malcolm Turnbull， 谴责了他们的”难以置信的马虎”</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>dual citizen</strong>: 双重国籍</li>
<li><strong>be in breach of</strong>: 违反</li>
<li><strong>incredible sloppiness</strong>: 难以置信的马虎</li>
<li><strong>deputy prime minister</strong>: 副总理</li>
<li><strong>diplomatic row</strong>: 外交争吵</li>
<li><strong>cast doubt on</strong>: 投下阴影</li>
<li><strong>cling to power</strong>: 掌握政权</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Australia’s constitution bans from the federal parliament anyone who is under “acknowledgment of allegiance, obedience or adherence to a foreign power”, or who is “a subject or a citizen or entitled to the rights or privileges of a subject or a citizen of a foreign power”. But in a country of high immigration, these strictures are causing unexpected political turmoil. In mid-July, Scott Ludlam of the Australian Greens resigned from the upper house, having just discovered he was a citizen of New Zealand. He left New Zealand when he was three, but never thought “citizenship sticks to you in that way”. A few days later Larissa Waters, the other deputy leader of the party, tearfully announced her resignation. She had been born in Canada and moved to Australia as a baby, but had never renounced her Canadian citizenship.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>澳洲宪法禁止任何”承认， 顺从或信奉国外势力的人”, 或者”属于他国臣民或公民， 或享有他国臣民或公民权利的人”加入联邦议会</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>ban from doing</strong>: 禁止做某事</li>
<li><strong>adherence to</strong>: 信奉</li>
<li><strong>stricture(n.)</strong>: 限制，约束</li>
<li><strong>stick to</strong>: 忠于</li>
<li><strong>tearfully(adv.)</strong>: 哭泣地</li>
<li><strong>renounce(v.)</strong>:宣布放弃</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>The circumstances of Matt Canavan, he former minister for resources, are even odder. The government was shaken when he declared on July 25th that he was both Italian and Australian. His mother, born in Australia to Italian parents, had secured Italian citizenship for herself and her son 11 years earlier. Mr Canavan says that he discovered this only when the citizenship row first erupted.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>前任资源部长，Matt Canavan的处境就更加离奇了。 当他在7月25号宣布他是意大利和澳洲双重国籍时，当局震惊了</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>erupt(v.)</strong>: 突然发出</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Mr Canavan gave up his ministerial post, but not his Senate seat. Mr Joyce, a fellow member of the National Party, the junior coalition partner, took over his portfolio. Just three weeks later, though, Mr Joyce told parliament he was “shocked” to learn that he was a Kiwi because his father had been born in New Zealand before moving to Australia in 1947.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Canavan放弃了他的部长职位，但是却保留了议员席位</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>ministerial post</strong>: 部长职位</li>
<li><strong>portfolio(n.)</strong>: 部长职位，大臣职位</li>
<li><strong>Kiwi(n.)</strong>: 新西兰人</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Mr Joyce has a habit of highlighting his rural roots by wearing cowboy hats and giving whip-cracking displays. He is famous for playing the indignant patriot in a row over quarantine laws with Johnny Depp, a Hollywood actor. The opposition is revelling in his predicament, especially as the government would lose its majority if he had to quit.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joyce有强调他乡村背景的习惯， 通过戴牛仔帽和做甩鞭秀</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>rural root</strong>: 乡村背景</li>
<li><strong>indignant patriot</strong>: 义愤的爱国者</li>
<li><strong>revel in</strong>: 陶醉于做…</li>
<li><strong>predicament(n.)</strong>: 困境, 尴尬的处境</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>The dual-citizenship question has added fuel to Australia’s already combustible politics. And the revelation that a staff member for a Labor senator had asked a New Zealand Labour MP about his country’s citizenship rules before Mr Joyce’s confession has turned the row into an international incident. Julie Bishop, Australia’s foreign minister, accused New Zealand’s Labour opposition of being “involved in allegations designed to undermine the government of Australia”. Not so, retorted Jacinda Ardern, New Zealand’s opposition leader. Undaunted, Mr Turnbull charged Australia’s opposition of con- spiring “with a foreign power”.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>双重国籍问题给本已纷争不断的政治事务加了一把火。并且一个爆料称一个竞选工党议员的成员在Joyce的供认之前，向新西兰劳工部长询问他们国家的公民身份政策， 这个爆料将争议转换成了国际冲突</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>add fuel to</strong>: 推波助澜</li>
<li><strong>combustible politics</strong>: 不可预测的政治</li>
<li><strong>undermine(v.)</strong>: 暗中破坏</li>
<li><strong>undaunted(adj.)</strong>: 不屈不挠的</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>If this was a ploy to deflect embarrassment over Mr Joyce, it fell flat. It could damage trans-Tasman relations if Ms Ardern’s party wins the general election due next month. And it ignores mounting calls to reform parliamentary citizenship rules drawn up in the 1890s, when Australia was still a colony of British subjects. The latest census, in 2016, revealed that 26% of Australians were born overseas; more than 300 languages are now spoken.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>如果这是一个将尴尬转向Joyce的花招， 明显没有达到效果</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>ploy(n.)</strong>: 策略，花招<br>e.g. a delaying ploy 拖延手段</li>
<li><strong>fall flat</strong>: 没达到效果</li>
<li><strong>mounting(adj.)</strong>: 增长的，加剧的</li>
<li><strong>drawn up</strong>: 起草，制定</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>On August 24th the High Court is due to start considering the case of the many dual-citizen MPs. Six have admitted doubts about their status; others have denied claims that they hold two nationalities. Mr Joyce has hurriedly renounced his New Zealand citizenship. Mr Turnbull argues he is qualified to stay in parliament “and the High Court will so hold”. A rash claim, say some constitutional experts. George Williams, of the University of New South Wales, thinks all five politicians could be “in great difficulty” if they were dual citizens when first elected. There will be growing pressure to change the constitution. But any reform may come too late to help the beleaguered Mr Turnbull.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>在8月24日， 最高法院预定开始着手处理多起双重国籍的部长的案件</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>be due to</strong>: 预定做某事</li>
<li><strong>a rash claim</strong>: 一项草率的声明</li>
<li><strong>constitutional expert</strong>: 宪法专家</li>
<li><strong>in great difficulty</strong>: 陷入大麻烦</li>
<li><strong>beleaguered(adj.)</strong>: 处于困境的，饱受职责的</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h1 id=&quot;Double-trouble&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Double-trouble&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Double trouble&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Double trouble&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;文章选自2017/8/19的The Econ
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CoolDown 经济学人阅读(27) - where the twain shall meet</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2017/08/20/where/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2017/08/20/where/</id>
    <published>2017-08-20T08:34:03.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-20T08:34:52.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="where-the-twain-shall-meet"><a href="#where-the-twain-shall-meet" class="headerlink" title="where the twain shall meet"></a>where the twain shall meet</h1><p>文章选自2017/8/05的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>导读: 一带一路计划提高了中国的影响力， 刺激了全球的经济发展， 无疑是有利于世界发展的好事。 一些西方企业虽然从中获利， 但也发现， 自己并非是最大收益者， 中国企业才是真正的主角。 他们一路陪跑， 深深担忧自己未来的发展</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li><p>分歧何时消除</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Mutual benefit, joint responsibility and shared destiny,” sings a choir of enthusiastic schoolgirls in a music video called “The Belt and Road, Sing Along” from Xinhua, a news service run by the Chinese government, that mixes shots of cranes and shipping containers with people enjoying foreign landmarks. Western firms are scarcely less optimistic. Launched by China in 2013, the One Belt, One Road policy, known as OBOR, has two parts. There is a land-based “belt” from China to Europe, evoking old Silk Road trade paths, then a “road” referring to ancient maritime routes.</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
<li><p><strong>mutual benefit</strong>: 互惠互利</p>
</li>
<li><strong>joint responsibility</strong>: 共担的责任</li>
<li><strong>shared destiny</strong>: 共同的命运</li>
<li><strong>choir(n.)</strong>: 合唱</li>
<li><strong>shot(n.)</strong>: 一段影片</li>
<li><strong>scarcely(adv.)</strong>: 几乎不</li>
<li><strong>maritime route</strong>: 航海路线</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>OBOR will span 65 countries (see map on next page), and China has so far invested over $900bn in projects ranging from highways in Pakistan to railway lines in Thailand. Western multinationals, spotting a bonanza, are selling billions of dollars of equipment, technology and services to Chinese firms building along it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>一带一路计划将扩展到65个国家， 并且中国目前已经投资了超过9000亿美元的项目， 包括巴基斯坦的高速公路项目到泰国的铁路项目。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>spot a bonanza</strong>: 看到一个发财机遇</li>
<li><strong>multinational(n.)</strong>: 跨国公司</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>America’s General Electric (GE) made sales of $2.3bn in equipment orders from OBOR projects in 2016, almost three times the total for the previous year. John Rice, the firm’s vice-chair, expects the firm to enjoy double-digit growth in revenues along OBOR in coming years. Other firms, such as Caterpillar, Honeywell, and ABB, global engineering giants, DHL, a logistics company, Linde and BASF, two industrial gas and chemicals manufacturers, and Maersk Group, a shipping firm, rattle off lists of OBOR projects. Deutsche Bank has structured eight trade deals around it and has an agreement with the China Development Bank, one of China’s policy lenders, to fund several OBOR schemes.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>美国通用公司在2016接到了几笔来自一带一路计划的总价值23亿美元的设备订单， 几乎是之前一年总额的三倍。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>make a sale of</strong>: 做成一笔买卖</li>
<li><strong>vice-chair</strong>: 副主席</li>
<li><strong>double-digit growth</strong>: 两位数的增长</li>
<li><strong>a logistics company</strong>: 一个物流公司</li>
<li><strong>rattle off</strong>: 不假思索地说出， 一口气写出</li>
<li><strong>policy lender</strong>: 政策性银行</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>All the activity has confounded early sceptics. They noted that in the past 15 years as China industrialised, the country’s companies ran construction projects over an expanse approximately equivalent to the built area of all western Europe with very little help from foreign firms.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>所有这些活动已经使早期的怀疑者震惊不已。他们强调在过去的15年中，随着中国的工业化， 在几乎没有外国公司的帮助下， 这个国家的进行的建造项目覆盖了广泛的区域， 几乎等于所有欧洲国家的建成区域。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>confound(v.)</strong>:使…惊讶</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Yet OBOR has highlighted that Chinese groups have little experience abroad, and that their Western counterparts offer a technological edge and thorough knowledge of local conditions across the OBOR region, from Tajikistan to Thailand. Partnering with Western multinationals also gives Chinese companies credibility, particularly with financial institutions. One Western executive admits that Chinese companies make liberal use of his firm’s name in OBOR project presentations to raise finance even though it is only marginally involved.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>并且， 一带一路计划突出了中国集团几乎没有国外经验， 并且他们的西方同行提供了先进技术和遍及一带一路区域的地缘知识， 从塔吉克斯坦到泰国。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>technological edge</strong>: 科技优势</li>
<li><strong>credibility(n.)</strong>: 可信度</li>
<li><strong>project presentation</strong>: 项目陈述</li>
<li><strong>raise finance</strong>: 募集资金</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Below the belt<br>Some executives worry that OBOR may have its downsides in the longer term. China wants to open up new markets for Chinese firms in sectors that are currently dominated by Western companies, across industries ranging from engineering and telecoms to shipping and e-commerce. Western firms are profiting handsomely from OBOR itself, but Chinese ones even more so. A database of open-source information collated by the Reconnecting Asia Project, run by the Centre for Strategic and International Studies, a think-tank in Washington, DC, shows that 86% of OBOR projects have Chinese contractors, 27% have local ones and only 18% have contractors of foreign origin.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>一些行政长官担心一带一路计划在长期来看也许有负面影响。 中国想为目前被西方公司主导的行业的中国企业打开市场， 从工程，电信行业到运输，电子商务行业。 西方企业正可观地从一带一路中盈利， 但中国企业盈利更多。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>sector(n.)</strong>: 行业</li>
<li><strong>handsomely(adv.)</strong>: 可观地</li>
<li><strong>think-tank</strong>: 智库</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Chinese firms are moving beyond contract work to become operators of projects and investors too. Their Western competitors may win lots of business in the OBOR countries only for as long as their technological advantage lasts. That lead in turn will be eroded as Western companies work with Chinese partners on OBOR. In 2016 alone, ABB did business with more than 400 Chinese enterprises, helping them adjust for huge differences in construction and engineering standards across countries. Such firms will learn and advance in the process.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>中国公司正从合同工作到成为项目的策划者和投资者。 他们的西方竞争者也许只有保持科技优势，才会从一带一路计划的国家中赢得更多商机。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Yet for now, Western companies are focused on the opportunities. Jean-Pascal Tri-coire, the Hong Kong-based chief executive of Schneider Electric, a French energy-services firm, says that for his company OBOR is one of the most important plans of the early part of this century. Honeywell has recently formed a team called “East to Rest” that manages sales and marketing to mainland firms that are expanding abroad. As a goateed singer in Xinhua’s music video promises Chinese viewers, “when Belt and Road reaches Europe, Europe’s red wine is delivered to the doorstep half a month earlier”. For years to come, OBOR looks likely to be the toast of Western boardrooms, too.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>然而到目前为止， 西方公司正聚焦在机会上。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>energy-services firm</strong>: 能源供应公司</li>
<li><strong>be the toast of</strong>: 备受推崇</li>
<li><strong>boardroom(n.)</strong>: 董事会</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h1 id=&quot;where-the-twain-shall-meet&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#where-the-twain-shall-meet&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;where the twain shall meet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;where th
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="English Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CoolDown 经济学人阅读(26) - A wild idea</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2017/08/15/a-wild-idea/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2017/08/15/a-wild-idea/</id>
    <published>2017-08-15T10:01:36.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-15T10:02:21.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="A-wild-idea"><a href="#A-wild-idea" class="headerlink" title="A wild idea"></a>A wild idea</h1><p>文章选自2017/8/05的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>导读： 人类使用动物来制作标识， 然后形成文化， 宣传品牌。 那么这些从动物形象中获益的集团， 是否应该承担起保护这种动物的责任呢？</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>一个大胆的想法。 wildlife, 是野生动物的意思。 题目也暗含了野生动物的寓意。</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Might those who profit from images of wildlife be induced to help save it?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>那些通过野生动物图片获利的人有可能被说服去保护野生动物吗？</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>be induced to do</strong>: 被劝说去做某事</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>MEERKATS are endearing creatures.Indeed, they are so endearing that they have been turned into characters in a long-running series of advertisements on British television for a price-comparison website. But nothing comes from nothing. Thirty years ago, few non-zoologists would have heard of these social mongooses and the joke would not have worked. The animals were brought to public prominence by a television documentary, “Meerkats United”, which described the doings of a group of them in the Kalahari, where they live. That documentary relied, in turn, on a research project run by David Macdonald, a zoologist at Oxford University. In essence, meerkats as a cultural phenomenon were created by this project.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>蒙哥是当下一种风靡的生物。 事实上， 它们如此受欢迎以至于已经被制作成一个在英国电视台播出的，为一个比价网站宣传的长篇系列广告。 但一切绝非无中生有。三十年前， 除了生物学家几乎很少有人听说过这种群居的獴，进而这个梗也不会奏效。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>endearing(adj.)</strong>: 讨人喜欢的</li>
<li><strong>a long-running series</strong>: 长期联播的系列节目</li>
<li><strong>a price-comparison website</strong>: 比价网站</li>
<li><strong>zoologist(n.)</strong>: 动物学家</li>
<li><strong>hear of</strong>: 得知</li>
<li><strong>public prominence</strong>: 公共声望</li>
<li><strong>the Kalahari</strong>: 卡拉哈里沙漠</li>
<li><strong>in essence</strong>: 实质上</li>
<li><strong>a cultural phenomenon</strong>: 文化现象</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Had that creation been purely artistic, it would be protected by copyright. Royalties derived from such copyright might then have been used for further study and conservation of the animals in question. Sadly for zoologists, the natural world is not covered by copyright and no royalties have ensued. But Dr Macdonald and two colleagues, Caroline Good and Dawn Burnham, writing in Animals, still wonder if those who profit by cultural representations of wildlife might sometimes be induced to contribute a sliver of their profits to the conservation of the animals so represented.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>鉴于那样的创作是纯粹的艺术， 它应该受版权保护。 从这样的版权中衍生的版税理应被用到进一步的研究和保护濒危动物。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>royalty(n.)</strong>: 版税</li>
<li><strong>cultural representation</strong>: 文化象征</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Rather than the meerkat, the three researchers take as their example a species with a longer history of public perception, the lion. Another project in which Dr Macdonald is involved is a study of lions in Zimbabwe. This was in the news recently when one of the animals being followed was shot, legally, by an American hunter after it had strayed out of a protected area. Lots of other lions are killed illegally, though—a phenomenon that might be reduced if more people were paid to protect them.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>除了蒙哥之外， 这三个研究员使用了另外一个有更长的公众认同历史的物种 – 狮子， 作为他们的范例。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>take as</strong>: 认为， 承认</li>
<li><strong>public perception</strong>: 公众看法， 公众认识</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Going for the throat, as it were, the three researchers observe that the English Premier League, the richest in soccer, has a crowned lion as its logo. They suggest that if the league chipped in, say, £1 ($1.30), for each of the 5m T-shirts sold every year bearing this logo, that would buy a lot of local recruits to lion-protection schemes in places where lions are under threat. It would also, they imagine, buy a lot of good publicity for the league itself.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>直击要害， 这三位研究员盯上了世界上最富有的足球联盟–英超，有一只戴皇冠的狮子作为标识。 他们建议如果联盟能在每年卖出的五百万件T-恤中，每一件捐出1英镑， 就能够雇佣许多当地的雇员来加入狮子保护计划。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>go for the throat</strong>: 直击要害</li>
<li><strong>chip in</strong>: 凑钱<br>e.g. He chipped in with $5. 他凑了5美元</li>
<li><strong>bear this logo</strong>: 带有这个商标</li>
<li><strong>publicity(n.)</strong>: 宣传</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>If the league were amenable, this idea might well work. But caution is advisable when choosing collaborators for such ventures. Conservationists thought they were onto a good thing in 2014 when, at the behest of local researchers, the mascot chosen for the Brazilian World Cup was a three-banded armadillo. At the outset, the proposal was that FIFA, the world governing body of football, and the Brazilian government would jointly pay for the protection of 1,000 hectares of armadillo habitat for every goal scored in the competition. The merchandising of the mascot, dubbed Fuleco, a portmanteau of “Futebol” and “Ecologia”, raised millions of dollars. The conservationists are still, however, waiting for the promised forest to be set aside. Both FIFA and the government, beset by other woes, seem to have forgotten about the idea.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>如果联盟有服从义务， 这个主意也许会奏效。 但是对于这项投资的合作者的选择仍需谨慎。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>amenable(adj.)</strong>:有服从义务的</li>
<li><strong>at the behest of</strong>: 按某人的吩咐</li>
<li><strong>mascot(n.)</strong>: 吉祥物</li>
<li><strong>armadillo(n.)</strong>: 犰狳</li>
<li><strong>at the outset</strong>: 起初</li>
<li><strong>set aside</strong>: 搁置一旁</li>
<li><strong>beset(v.)</strong>: 受…困扰</li>
<li><strong>forget about</strong>: 忘记某事，某人</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h1 id=&quot;A-wild-idea&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#A-wild-idea&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;A wild idea&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A wild idea&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;文章选自2017/8/05的The Economist。 这里对文章
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="English Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CoolDown 经济学人阅读(25) - It could happen(2)</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2017/08/13/itcouldhappen/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2017/08/13/itcouldhappen/</id>
    <published>2017-08-13T11:50:33.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-13T11:51:21.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="It-could-happen"><a href="#It-could-happen" class="headerlink" title="It could happen"></a>It could happen</h1><p>文章选自2017/8/05的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Can Mr Kim be cajoled or bribed into giving up his nuclear ambitions? It is worth trying, but has little chance of success. In 1994 President Bill Clinton secured a deal whereby Kim Jong Il (the current despot’s father) agreed to stop producing the raw material for nuclear bombs in return for a huge injection of aid. Kim took the money and technical help, but immediately started cheating. Another deal in 2005 failed, for the same reason. The younger Kim, like his father, sees nuclear weapons as the only way to guarantee the survival of his regime. It is hard to imagine circumstances in which he would voluntarily give up what he calls his “treasured sword of justice”.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>金先生能被劝诱或者贿赂以至于放弃他的有核化目标？这值得尝试， 但是几乎没有成功的可能。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>cajole(v.)</strong>: 劝诱</li>
<li><strong>secure a deal</strong>: 确保一个交易</li>
<li><strong>whereby</strong>: 因此</li>
<li><strong>despot(n.)</strong>: 专制君主</li>
<li><strong>in turn</strong>: 转而</li>
<li><strong>a huge injection of</strong>: 对…的大量投入</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>If military action is reckless and diplomacy insufficient, the only remaining option is to deter and contain Mr Kim. Mr Trump should make clear—in a scripted speech, not a tweet or via his secretary of state—that America is not about to start a war, nuclear or conventional. However, he should reaffirm that a nuclear attack by North Korea on America or one of its allies will immediately be matched. Mr Kim cares about his own skin. He enjoys the life of a dissolute deity, living in a palace and with the power to kill or bed any of his subjects. If he were to unleash a nuclear weapon, he would lose his luxuries and his life. So would his cronies. That means they can be deterred.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>如果军事行动是莽撞的并且外交是徒劳的， 仅剩的选择就是威慑和限制金先生。 Trump应该明确表态–通过正式的演讲，而不是推特或者国务卿–美国不会发起核战争或者常规战争。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>reckless(adj.)</strong>: 鲁莽的，莽撞的</li>
<li><strong>a scripted speech</strong>: 精心组织的讲话</li>
<li><strong>secretary of state</strong>: 国务卿</li>
<li><strong>reaffirm(v.)</strong>:重申</li>
<li><strong>match(v.)</strong>: 与…相当, 同等对待</li>
<li><strong>care about his own skin</strong>: 保全自己<br>extend: save one’s own skin 保全自己</li>
<li><strong>a dissolute deity</strong>: 道德沦丧的神</li>
<li><strong>bed his subjects</strong>: 与他的臣民行房事</li>
<li><strong>crony(n.)</strong>: 密友</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>To contain Mr Kim, America and its allies should apply pressure that cannot be misconstrued as a declaration of war. They should ramp up economic sanctions not only against the North Korean regime but also against the Chinese companies that trade with it or handle its money. America should formally extend its nuclear guarantee to South Korea and Japan, and boost the missile defences that protect both countries. This would help ensure that they do not build nuclear weapons of their own. America should convince the South Koreans, who will suffer greatly if war breaks out, that it will not act without consulting them.China is fed up with the Kim regime, but fears that if it were to collapse, a reunified Korea would mean American troops on China’s border. Mr Trump’s team should guarantee that this will not happen, and try to persuade China that in the long run it is better off with a united, prosperous neighbour than a poor, violent and unpredictable one.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>为了遏制金先生， 美国与其盟友需要施加压力，并且不让其为误解为战争的宣言。 他们应该加强对朝鲜政权的经济制裁并且阻止中国企业与其贸易或者接收它的钱。 美国应该有条理地扩展其核防御到韩国和日本， 并加速其用于保护这两国的导弹防御建设。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>contain(v.)</strong>: 遏制</li>
<li><strong>apply pressure</strong>: 施加压力</li>
<li><strong>ramp up economic sanctions</strong>: 增加经济制裁</li>
<li><strong>handle its money</strong>: 碰它的钱</li>
<li><strong>extend its guarantee</strong>: 扩大其保障</li>
<li><strong>boost the missile defenses</strong>: 促进导弹防御</li>
<li><strong>be fed up with</strong>: 受够了</li>
<li><strong>reunified(adj.)</strong>: 重新统一的</li>
<li><strong>be better off</strong>: 处于更好的处境</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Everyone stay calm<br>All the options for dealing with the North are bad. Although America should not recognise it as a legitimate nuclear power, it must base its policy on the reality that it is already an illegitimate one. Mr Kim may gamble that his nukes give him the freedom to behave more provocatively, perhaps sponsoring terrorism in the South. He may also sell weapons to other cruel regimes or terrorist groups. The world must do what it can to thwart such plots, though some will doubtless succeed.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>所有的处理朝鲜问题的选择都是不好的。 尽管美国不认可它是合法的核力量， 但是美国的政策仍然需要建立在事实基础上–朝鲜已经成为了非法的核力量。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>legitimate(adj.)</strong>: 合法的</li>
<li><strong>illegitimate(adj.)</strong>: 不合法的</li>
<li><strong>nuke(n.)</strong>: 核武器</li>
<li><strong>provocatively(adv.)</strong>: 挑衅地</li>
<li><strong>thwart plots</strong>: 挫败阴谋</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>It is worth recalling that America has been here before. When Stalin and Mao were building their first atom bombs, some in the West urged pre-emptive strikes to stop them. Happily, cooler heads prevailed. Since then, the logic of deterrence has ensured that these terrible weapons have never been used. Some day, perhaps by coup or popular uprising, North Koreans will be rid of their repulsive ruler, and the peninsula will reunite as a democracy, like Germany. Until then, the world must keep calm and contain Mr Kim.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>值得回忆的是，美国曾今走到这步田地。 当斯大林和毛正在建造各自的第一枚原子弹时， 一些西方势力呼吁提前采取打击来阻止他们。令人庆幸的是， 冷静的头脑占据了上风。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>coup(n.)</strong>: 政变</li>
<li><strong>popular uprising</strong>: 人民起义</li>
<li><strong>be rid of</strong>: 摆脱</li>
<li><strong>repulsive ruler</strong>: 令人反感的统治者</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h1 id=&quot;It-could-happen&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#It-could-happen&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;It could happen&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;It could happen&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;文章选自2017/8/05的The 
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="English Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CoolDown 经济学人阅读(24) - It could happen(1)</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2017/08/12/it-could-happen/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2017/08/12/it-could-happen/</id>
    <published>2017-08-11T14:57:14.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-11T14:58:02.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="It-could-happen"><a href="#It-could-happen" class="headerlink" title="It could happen"></a>It could happen</h1><p>文章选自2017/8/05的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流</p>
<blockquote>
<p>导读: 金正恩搞定洲际导弹有一段时间了。 Trump软硬兼施，联合中国，制裁朝鲜， 却依然不能拔掉这枚指甲缝里的刺。 美朝之战，也许会一触即发。</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>对美国来说， 也许一场战争才是平息朝鲜核问题的方法。</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>There are no good options to curb Kim Jong Un’s missile-building. But blundering into war would be the worst</p>
</blockquote>
<p>没有好的选择来限制金正恩的导弹建设计划。 但无意中引发战争将是更糟的结果</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>curb(v.)</strong>: 限制</li>
<li><strong>bludering</strong>: 不慎陷入</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>IT IS odd that North Korea causes so much trouble. It is not exactly a superpower. Its<br>economy is only a fiftieth as big as that of its democratic capitalist cousin, South Korea. Americans spend twice its total GDP on their pets. Yet Kim Jong Un’s<br>backward little dictatorship has grabbed the attention of the whole world, and even of America’s president, with its nuclear brinkmanship. On July 28th it tested an intercontinental ballistic missile that could hit Los Angeles. Before long, it will be able to mount nuclear warheads on such missiles, as it already can on missiles aimed at South Korea and Japan. In charge of this terrifying arsenal is a man who was brought up as a demigod and cares nothing for human life—witness the innocents beaten to death with hammers in his gigantic gulag. Last week his foreign ministry vowed that if the regime’s “supreme dignity” is threatened, it will “pre-emptively annihilate” the countries that threaten it, with all means “including the nuclear ones”. Only a fool could fail to be alarmed.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>朝鲜能制造这么多麻烦真是令人感到奇怪。 它并不是一个超级大国。 经济规模只有它的民主资本主义姊妹，韩国的1/15。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>odd(adj.)</strong>: 奇怪的，古怪的<br>e.g. He’d always been odd, but not to this extent. 他一直比较怪异，不过并没有到这种程度。</li>
<li><strong>dictatorship(n.)</strong>: 专政，独裁</li>
<li><strong>grab the attention of</strong>: 吸引…的注意力</li>
<li><strong>brinkmanship(n.)</strong>: 边缘政策，不断将外交形势推至战争边缘，以试探对手国的忍耐极限，以获取最大利益</li>
<li><strong>intercontinental ballistic missile</strong>: 洲际弹道导弹</li>
<li><strong>in charge of</strong>: 负责</li>
<li><strong>gigantic gulag</strong>: 巨型集中营</li>
<li><strong>regime(n.)</strong>: 政权</li>
<li><strong>annihilate(v.)</strong>: 彻底击败，摧毁</li>
<li><strong>pre-emptively(adv.)</strong>: 首先行动</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>What another Korean war might look like<br>Yet the most serious danger is not that one side will suddenly try to devastate the other. It is that both sides will miscalculate, and that a spiral of escalation will lead to a catastrophe that no one wants. Our briefing this week lays out, step by step, one way that America and North Korea might blunder into a nuclear war (see page 14). It also lists some of the likely consequences. These include: for North Korea, the destruction of its regime and the death of hundreds of thousands of people. For SouthKorea,the destruction of Seoul, a city of 10m within easy range of 1,000 of the North’s conventional artillery pieces. For America, the possibility of a nuclear attack on one of its garrisons in East Asia, or even on an American city. And don’t forget the danger of an armed confrontation between America and China, the North’s neighbour and grudging ally. It seems distasteful to mention the economic effects of another Korean war, but they would of course be awful, too.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>到目前为止， 最严重的危险不是一边突然试图毁灭另一边。而是两边都判断错误， 并且日益恶化的局势将引发没人期望的大灾难。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>devastate(v.)</strong>: 摧毁，毁灭</li>
<li><strong>a spiral of escalation</strong>: 日益恶化</li>
<li><strong>lay out a briefing</strong>: 阐述报告</li>
<li><strong>artillery piece</strong>: 大炮</li>
<li><strong>garrison(n.)</strong>: 驻防部队</li>
<li><strong>armed confrontation</strong>:武装冲突</li>
<li><strong>grudging ally</strong>: 积怨的盟友</li>
<li><strong>be distasteful to</strong>: 令某人反感的</li>
<li><strong>economic effect</strong>: 经济影响</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>President Donald Trump has vowed to stop North Korea from perfecting a nuclear warhead that could threaten the American mainland, tweeting that “it won’t happen!” Some pundits suggest shooting down future test missiles on the launchpad or, improbably, in the air. Others suggest using force to overthrow the regime or pre-emptive strikes to destroy Mr Kim’s nuclear arsenal before he has a chance to use it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Trump已经发誓要阻止朝鲜完善一枚能威胁到美国本土的核弹头， 并发推声称“不会发生！”有些行家建议在发射台上就击落将要测试的导弹， 甚至， 不太可能地，在空中拦截。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>pundit(n.)</strong>: 行家</li>
<li><strong>shoot down</strong>: 击落</li>
<li><strong>overthrow a regime</strong>: 推翻政权</li>
<li><strong>pre-emptive strike</strong>: 先发制人的行动</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Yet it is just this sort of military action that risks a ruinous escalation. Mr Kim’s bombs and missile-launchers are scattered and well hidden. America’s armed forces, for all their might, cannot reliably neutralise the North Korean nuclear threat before Mr Kim has a chance to retaliate. The task would be difficult even if the Pentagon had good intelligence about North Korea; it does not. The only justification for a pre-emptive strike would be to prevent an imminent nuclear attack on America or one of its allies.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>然而， 正是这种军事行动冒着冲突升级的危险。 金先生的炸弹和导弹发射器被分散了且妥善隐藏了。 美国军队，竭尽所能也不能在金先生有机会报复之前消除朝鲜核威胁。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>military action</strong>: 军事行动</li>
<li><strong>ruinous escalation</strong>: 毁灭性的升级</li>
<li><strong>for all their might</strong>: 竭尽所能</li>
<li><strong>neutralise the nuclear threat</strong>: 消除(抵消)核威胁</li>
<li><strong>retaliate(v.)</strong>: 报复</li>
<li><strong>imminent(adj.)</strong>: 迫近的</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h1 id=&quot;It-could-happen&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#It-could-happen&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;It could happen&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;It could happen&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;文章选自2017/8/05的The 
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="English Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CoolDown 经济学人阅读(23) - Harlem shuffle</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2017/08/09/harlem-shuffle/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2017/08/09/harlem-shuffle/</id>
    <published>2017-08-09T08:41:21.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-09T08:45:26.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Harlem-shuffle"><a href="#Harlem-shuffle" class="headerlink" title="Harlem shuffle"></a>Harlem shuffle</h1><p>文章选自2017/7/29的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>导读： 本文讨论了纽约几个区改名字的历史。</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li><strong>Harlem shuffle</strong>: 滚石的一首老歌， 在这里比喻纽约路名的变迁<blockquote>
<p>Why some names stick and others do not</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
</ul>
<p>为什么一些名字还在使用， 一些却不再使用了</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>stick(v.)</strong>: 仍在使用<br>e.g. They called him ‘Snoopy’ at school, and the name stuck. 有人在学校叫他“史努比”, 后来这名字就叫开了。</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>HARLEM’S Apollo Theatre, where Ella Fitzgerald first sang, and the Hotel Theresa, which counted among its guests Josephine Baker, Muhammad Ali and Fidel Castro, are landmarks. Malcolm X, who called Harlem “Seventh Heaven”, preached on the corner of 116th Street. Stretching further back, in the 1920s and 1930s the Harlem Renaissance gave rise to an outpouring of literature, art and music. Harlemites are proud of this history, and proportionately upset that estate agents are trying to rebrand the southern part and call it SoHa.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>哈林区的地标有：Ella Fitzgerald的首演地–阿波罗剧院， 还有被Josephine Baker，Muhammad Ali和Fidel Castro高度赞扬的特蕾莎旅馆。  </p>
<ul>
<li><strong>count(v.)</strong>: 有价值，重要<br>e.g. Every second counts! 每秒钟都很重要</li>
<li><strong>an outpouring of</strong>: 迸发，井喷<br>e.g. an outpouring of grief 悲伤情绪的宣泄</li>
<li><strong>give rise to</strong>: 带来，导致</li>
<li><strong>preach(v.)</strong>: 布道，宣传</li>
<li><strong>proportionately(adv.)</strong>: 相应地</li>
<li><strong>upset(v.)</strong>: 打乱，搅乱<br>e.g. A deal that would upset the balance of power in the world’s gold markets. 一桩将会打破全球黄金市场均势的交易</li>
<li><strong>estate agent</strong>: 不动产经纪人</li>
<li><strong>rebrand(v.)</strong>: 重塑…的形象(企业)<br>e.g. There are plans to rebrand many Texas stores. 有计划要重塑德克萨斯州诸多门店的品牌形象</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Such rebranding is nothing new: New York was once called Nieuw Amsterdam and before that Mannahatta. Pigtown, in central Brooklyn, is now called Wingate. Gas House District is now Stuyvesant Town. Yellow Hook became Bay Ridge after a yellow-fever outbreak. Blooming-dale became the Upper West Side. Neighbourhoods can be fluid, with vague borders. Some have disappeared. Shapes change: in Brooklyn, Park Slope keeps getting bigger and Flatbush keeps getting smaller. Chinatown has been taking over Little Italy.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>这样的重建并不少见：纽约曾被叫做Nieuw Amsterdam，在那之前叫做Mannahatta. Pigtown，在中央布鲁克林，现在叫做Wingate.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>yellow fever</strong>: 黄热病</li>
<li><strong>fluid(adj.)</strong>: 流动的，不稳定的</li>
<li><strong>vague border</strong>: 模糊的边界</li>
<li><strong>take over</strong>: 取代，替代</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>SoHo, so-called because it is south of Houston Street, was better known until the 1960s as Hell’s Hundred Acres. It was the first to use an acronym, and has spawned imitators. Tribeca (triangle below Canal Street) emerged in the 1970s. Despite, or perhaps because of, its silly name, Dumbo (Down Under the Manhattan Bridge Overpass) is one of the most sought-after areas in the city. NoHo (north of Houston) and NoLita (North of Little Italy) are now on maps. Others, like SoBro (south Bronx), BoCoCa (Carroll Gardens, Cobble Hill and Boreum Hill, which is in fact flat) and Rambo (Right after the Manhattan Bridge Overpass), mercifully did not stick. “None of these worked,” says Philip Kasinitz, a sociologist at City University of New York. “At a certain point they got too silly.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>SoHo, 被这么叫是因为它位于休斯顿街， 闻名于六十年代创建的步行街–Hell’s Hundred Acres. 这个区首次使用了缩写做名字， 并派生了许多模仿者。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>sought-after(adj.)</strong>:受欢迎的</li>
<li><strong>overpass(n.)</strong>: 天桥</li>
<li><strong>mercifully(adv.)</strong>: 仁慈地</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>They also didn’t work, he says, because their residents objected. ProCro, a rebranding of Crown Heights, another historically black neighbourhood in Brooklyn, did not take either. Hell’s Kitchen is equally resilient. Attempts to change the name to the generic Clinton have not been successful. It is a lot easier to rebrand when there are few residents, as was the case in SoHo. Brokers also rely on recent arrivals not knowing the city well.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>它们同样没有效果， 他说， 因为它们的邻居都拒绝这样做。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>resilient(adj.)</strong>: 适应能力强的</li>
<li><strong>generic(adj.)</strong>: 普通的</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>“You can’t talk about this without talking about race,” says Amy Plitt of Curbed, a property blog. Affluent white New Yorkers have flocked to Harlem, followed by restaurants, bars and shops. The stock of cheap housing has dwindled. Longtime residents, already feeling financial pressure, resent what they see as a deliberate move to erase their history. “It’s about identity,” said Brian Benjamin, a Harlem-born state lawmaker. He recently introduced legislation in Albany requiring estate agents to consult the community on any name change, or face a fine. Others see a clumsy attempt to link SoHa to SoHo in the minds of would-be buyers, making it cooler and justifying higher prices. But nowhere is cooler than Harlem.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>“讨论这问题一定要考虑竞争的因素，” 一个房地产博客， Amy Plitt of Curbed 如是说。 富裕的纽约白人涌入了哈林区， 带来了大量的餐厅，酒吧和商店。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>property blog</strong>: 房地产博客</li>
<li><strong>dwindle(v.)</strong>: 逐渐消失</li>
<li><strong>longtime resident</strong>: 长期住户</li>
<li><strong>financial pressure</strong>: 经济压力</li>
<li><strong>a deliberate move</strong>: 故意的举动</li>
<li><strong>lawmaker(n.)</strong>: 立法者</li>
<li><strong>face a fine</strong>: 面临罚款</li>
<li><strong>a clumsy attempt</strong>: 不得当的尝试</li>
<li><strong>would-be buyer</strong>: 潜在的买家</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h1 id=&quot;Harlem-shuffle&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Harlem-shuffle&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Harlem shuffle&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Harlem shuffle&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;文章选自2017/7/29的The Econ
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="English Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CoolDown 经济学人阅读(22) - Code red</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2017/08/05/code-red/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2017/08/05/code-red/</id>
    <published>2017-08-05T01:31:03.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-05T01:31:47.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Code-red"><a href="#Code-red" class="headerlink" title="Code red"></a>Code red</h1><p>文章选自2017/7/29的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>导读： 拥有海量数据， 众多人才， 政府扶持。 中国无疑是AI发展的乐土。 但是安全与道德的问题，该如何约束</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>红色代码: 暗指国家扶持的人工智能项目， 同时也存在危险性<blockquote>
<p>State-controlled corporations are developing powerful artificial intelligence. That is worrying</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
</ul>
<p>国有企业正在开发强大的人工智能，这令人忧心忡忡</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>state-controlled corporations</strong>:国有企业</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>IMAGINE the perfect environment for developing artificial intelligence (AI). The ingredients would include masses of processing power, lots of computer-science boffins, a torrent of capital—and abundant data with which to train machines to recognise and respond to patterns. That environment might sound like a fair description of America, the current leader in the field. But in some respects it is truer still of China.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>想象一下发展人工智能的完美环境。 主要因素包含了海量处理能力， 众多的计算机科研人员， 源源不断的资金–以及用于训练的机器做模式识别的海量数据。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>masses of</strong>: 大量的</li>
<li><strong>computer-science boffin</strong>: 计算机科学科研工作者</li>
<li><strong>a torrent of</strong>: 迸发的，接连不断的</li>
<li><strong>a fair description</strong>: 有道理的说法</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>The country is rapidly building up its cloud-computing capacity.For sheer volume of research on AI,if not quality, Chinese academics surpass their American peers; AI-related patent submissions in China almost tripled between 2010 and 2014 compared with the previous five years. Chinese startups are attracting billions in venture capital. Above all, China has over 700m smartphone users, more than any other country. They are consuming digital services, using voice assistants, paying for stuff with a wave of their phones—and all the while generating vast quantities of data. That gives local firms such as Alibaba, Baidu and Tencent the opportunity to concoct best- in-class AI systems for everything from facial recognition to messaging bots. The government in Beijing is convinced of the potential. On July 20th it outlined a development strategy designed to make China the world’s leading AI power by 2030.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>中国正在迅速建立起云计算能力。 如果不算质量，从急剧增加的AI研究上来看， 中国学者已经超过了他们的美国同行；在中国AI相关的专利提交数量在2010到2014几乎增至之前五年的三倍。中国的创业公司正在吸引数十亿的风险资本。 除此之外， 中国拥有超过7亿智能手机用户， 远超过其他国家。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>cloud-computing</strong>: 云计算</li>
<li><strong>sheer volume of</strong>: 极其大量的</li>
<li><strong>patent submissions</strong>: 专利提交</li>
<li><strong>AI-related</strong>: 人工智能相关的</li>
<li><strong>venture capital</strong>: 风险资本</li>
<li><strong>above all</strong>: 更重要的是</li>
<li><strong>concoct(v.)</strong>: 调制，调配</li>
<li><strong>best-in-class</strong>: 一流的</li>
<li><strong>facial recognition</strong>: 面部识别</li>
<li><strong>messaging bots</strong>: 语音助手</li>
<li><strong>be convinced of</strong>: 确信…</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>An AI boom in the world’s most populous place holds out enormous promise. No other country could generate such a volume of data to enable machines to learn patterns indicative of rare diseases, for example. The development of new technologies ought to happen faster, too. Because typing Chinese characters is fiddly, voice-recognition services are more popular than in the West; they should improve faster as a result. Systems to adjust traffic lights automatically in response to footage from roadside cameras are already being tested. According to the McKinsey Global Institute, a research arm of the consultancy, AI-driven automation could boost China’s GDP growth by more than a percentage point annually.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>一股人工智能热潮在世界上人口最多的地方带来巨大的前景。 比如， 没有哪个国家能产生如此多的数据让机器去学习描述罕见疾病的模式。 新技术也应该进展飞速。 因为中文输入十分繁琐， 语音识别服务比在西方国家更流行；作为回应，它们应该迅速提升。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>AI boom</strong>: 人工智能热潮</li>
<li><strong>hold out enormous promise</strong>: 带来巨大的前景</li>
<li><strong>rare diseases</strong>: 罕见疾病</li>
<li><strong>adjust traffic lights</strong>: 调节交通灯</li>
<li><strong>research arm</strong>: 研究分支机构</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Yet the country’s AI plans also give cause for concern. One worry is that the benefits of Chinese breakthroughs will be muted by data protectionism. A cyber-security law that came into force in June requires foreign firms to store data they collect on Chinese customers within the country’s borders; outsiders cannot use Chinese data to offer services to third parties. It is not hard to imagine tit-for-tat constraints on Chinese firms. And if data cannot be pooled, the algorithms that run autonomous cars and other products may not be the most efficient.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>然而，中国的AI计划也令人忧心。 一个担心就是中国的技术突破带来的好处将被数据保护主义抑制。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>give cause for concern</strong>: 让人担心</li>
<li><strong>be muted by</strong>: 被削弱</li>
<li><strong>data protectionism</strong>:数据保护主义</li>
<li><strong>cyber-security law</strong>:网络安全法</li>
<li><strong>come into force</strong>: (法律)实施</li>
<li><strong>tit-for-tat constraint</strong>: 针锋相对的限制</li>
<li><strong>autonomous car</strong>: 自动驾驶汽车</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>A second area of unease is ethics and safety. In America, the technology giants of Silicon Valley have pledged to work together to make sure that any AI tools they develop are safe. They will look at techniques like “boxing”, in which AI agents are isolated from their environment so that any wayward behaviour does not have disastrous effects. All the leading AI researchers in the West are signatories to an open letter from 2015 calling for a ban on the creation of autonomous weapons. If it happens at all, the equivalent Chinese discussion about the limits of ethical AI research is far more opaque.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>另一个令人不安的问题就是道德和安全。 在美国， 硅谷的科技巨头已经承诺一起合作确保他们开发的AI工具是安全的。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>unease(n.)</strong>: 不安，担心</li>
<li><strong>wayward behaviour</strong>: 难以控制的行为</li>
<li><strong>disastrous effect</strong>: 灾难性的影响</li>
<li><strong>signatory</strong>: 缔约者</li>
<li><strong>open letter</strong>: 公开信</li>
<li><strong>opaque(n.)</strong>: 难懂的，不透明的</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Chinese AI companies do have incentives to think about some of these issues: rogue AI would be a problem for the planet wherever it emerged. There is a self-interested case for the formulation of global safety standards, for example. But a third concern—that AI will be used principally to the benefit of China’s government—is a less tractable problem.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>中国的AI公司有动机去思考一下下列问题： 无论在地球的哪个地方兴起， 流氓AI将会成为一个问题。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>have incentives to do</strong>: 有动机做…</li>
<li><strong>a self-interested case</strong>: 一个自私的例子</li>
<li><strong>principally(adv.)</strong>: 主要的</li>
<li><strong>a tractable problem</strong>: 易处理的的问题</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Autocratic intelligence<br>The new plan is open about AI’s value to the state. It envisages the use of the technology in everything from guided missiles to predictive policing. AI techniques are perfect for finding patterns in the massive amounts of data that Chinese censors must handle in order to maintain a grip on the citizenry. It is easy to imagine how the same data could boost the country’s nascent plans to create a “social-credit” system that scores people for their behaviour. Once perfected, these algorithms would interest autocratic regimes around the world. China’s tech firms are in no position to prevent the government in Beijing from taking advantage of such tools. Baidu, for example, has been appointed to lead a national laboratory for deep learning. Chinese AI will reflect the influence of the state.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>新计划对AI对国家的价值直言不讳。 设想了应用AI技术到各种事情，从制导导弹到可预测治安维护。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>be open about</strong>: 不隐瞒，直言不讳</li>
<li><strong>autocratic(adj.)</strong>: 独裁的</li>
<li><strong>envisage(v.)</strong>: 设想，展望</li>
<li><strong>predictive policing</strong>: 可预测治安维护</li>
<li><strong>censor(n.)</strong>: 审查者(负责人口普查，监督公众道德行为)</li>
<li><strong>a grip on</strong>: 对…的控制</li>
<li><strong>nascent plan</strong>: 新生的计划</li>
<li><strong>autocratic regime</strong>: 独裁政权</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Western firms and governments are no angels when it comes to data collection and espionage. But Western companies are at least engaged in an open debate about the ethical implications of AI; and intelligence agencies are constrained by democratic institutions. Neither is true of China. AI is a technology with the potential to change the lives of billions. If China ends up having most influence over its future, then the state, not citizens, may be the biggest beneficiary.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>当涉及数据收集和间谍活动时，西方政府和企业不会像天使那样纯洁无暇。 但西方企业至少参与到了一场由AI引起的道德问题的辩论当中；并且智能代理是受民主机构约束的。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>espionage(n.)</strong>:间谍活动</li>
<li><strong>ethical implication</strong>: 道德影响</li>
<li><strong>beneficiary(n.)</strong>: 受益人</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h1 id=&quot;Code-red&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Code-red&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Code red&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Code red&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;文章选自2017/7/29的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="English Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CoolDown 经济学人阅读(21) - The new gunboat diplomacy</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2017/08/01/gunboat/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2017/08/01/gunboat/</id>
    <published>2017-07-31T14:16:52.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-31T14:17:40.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="The-new-gunboat-diplomacy"><a href="#The-new-gunboat-diplomacy" class="headerlink" title="The new gunboat diplomacy"></a>The new gunboat diplomacy</h1><p>文章选自2017/7/29的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>导读: 中国的海军力量不断崛起， 并在远洋展示其军事能力。 西方国家需要接受这个既定的事实，并让中国参与到维护世界和平的活动中去，而不是处处隔离中国， 让敌意进一步加深。</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>新舰船外交</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>China is extending its maritime power across the world—but that is not necessarily a bad thing</p>
</blockquote>
<p>中国正在全球范围内扩展制海权–但这并不是坏事</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>maritime power</strong>: 制海权</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>RARELY in times of peace has a country acquired naval power at such a rate as China has in recent years. Three decades ago its warships were clapped out, capable of operating only close to shore. Now its shipyards are churning out state-of-the-art combat vessels at a furious pace. Some experts believe it could have as many warships as America within a few years. China’s navy is also developing global range: this week three of its ships have been staging war games in the Baltic Sea with the Russian navy, the first joint exercises by the two countries in those waters. The intended message to the West is clear. China and Russia, united in their resentment of American power, are thumbing their noses at NATO on its doorstep.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>在和平年代， 很少有国家可以以中国这几年的速度来得到制海权。三十年前，它的军舰能用于检阅，仅能保护近岸海域。 而现在， 它的造船厂正以激进的速度量产最先进的战舰。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>naval power</strong>: 制海权</li>
<li><strong>clap out</strong>: 鼓掌</li>
<li><strong>churn out</strong>: 大量炮制</li>
<li><strong>combat vessel</strong>: 作战船只</li>
<li><strong>a furious pace</strong>: 剧烈的节奏</li>
<li><strong>stage(v.)</strong>: 安排，组织</li>
<li><strong>joint exercise</strong>: 联合演习</li>
<li><strong>the intended message</strong>: 想要表达的讯息</li>
<li><strong>resentment(n.)</strong>: 憎恨</li>
<li><strong>thumb one’s noses at sth</strong>: 对…不屑一顾</li>
<li><strong>NATO</strong>: 北大西洋公约组织</li>
<li><strong>on one’s doorstep</strong>: 在某人家门口</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>China’s naval build-up worries American officials. Hardly a week goes by without some new development that troubles them. In April the country launched its first domestically built aircraft-carrier, and then in June its first 10,000-tonne destroy er—similar in size to the ones America deploys in the region. This month Chinese ships filled with troops sailed for Djibouti to set up the country’s first overseas military base. China’s naval build-up is giving it the wherewithal to seize and hold disputed territory to which it lays claim in the East and South China Seas, and to threaten Taiwan. In the event of a conflict, America could be drawn in. This week’s exercises with Russia in the Baltic, meanwhile, suggest not only a shared enmity towards the West but also mutual admiration of each other’s thuggish political systems. President Xi Jinping has turned a blind eye to Russia’s land-grab in Ukraine, and President Vladimir Putin to China’s in the South China Sea.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>中国海军的崛起引发了美国官方的担心。 近一周来的进展深深地困扰着他们。 4月份， 中国下水了他们的第一艘国产航母， 并在6月下水了10，000公吨的驱逐舰–与美国部署在同海域的那些有相同的吨位。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>build-up(n.)</strong>: 集聚， 增强</li>
<li><strong>destroyer(n.)</strong>: 驱逐舰</li>
<li><strong>military base</strong>: 军事基地</li>
<li><strong>wherewithal(n.)</strong>: 必要的资源，必要的财力<br>e.g. He hasn’t the wherewithal to buy it. 他没有钱买那个</li>
<li><strong>hold disputed territory</strong>: 控制争议领土</li>
<li><strong>draw in</strong>: 使卷入，使参与</li>
<li><strong>enmity(n.)</strong>: 敌意，不和<br>e.g. family feuds and enmities. 家族世仇和怨恨</li>
<li><strong>land-grab(n.)</strong>: 侵占领土</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Yet there is far less to the Russia-China relationship than meets the eye (see page 35). Russian officials worry about China’s growing economic and military might almost as much as their American counterparts do. Russia sells China a lot of weapons, but sells similar stuff to India, China’s rival. True, Mr Xi ignores the West’s sanctions on Russia—but that is mainly because he wants a stable relationship with a huge neighbour which China has come close to fighting in living memory.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>然而中俄关系远比呈现在我们眼前的要复杂。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>meet the eye</strong>: 呈现在眼前</li>
<li><strong>sanctions(n.)</strong>: 国际制裁</li>
<li><strong>in living memory</strong>: 至今被铭记的事情</li>
<li><strong>come close to</strong>: 接近于，近乎于</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Exercising responsibility<br>As for China’s naval muscle-flexing in the Baltic, that is a development that should, in several respects, be welcomed rather than feared. If China wants to show that its warships can operate in distant seas, there is nothing wrong with that. Indeed, it is entirely right that China, as a global economic power, should play a larger part in providing the maritime security on which global trade depends. It is already taking part in anti-piracy operations in the Gulf of Aden—something for which its base in Djibouti will play a useful supporting role.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>至于中国海军在波罗的海秀肌肉的事情， 从若干角度来看， 应该受到欢迎，而不是担忧。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>muscle-flexing</strong>: 武力炫耀</li>
<li><strong>in several respects</strong>: 在几方面看来</li>
<li><strong>distant seas</strong>: 远洋</li>
<li><strong>anti-piracy operations</strong>: 打击海盗的行动</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Deploying its navy far beyond its own waters might also help China understand that America, too, has good reasons for doing so. China frequently huffs about American warships in the western Pacific, refusing to accept one of the Pentagon’s main reasons for deploying there: that America has a vital stake in the security of Asian trade.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>在领海之外部署海军也许能帮助中国理解美国有同样的理由去这么做。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>huff(v.)</strong>: 愤愤不满， 生闷气</li>
<li><strong>a vital stake</strong>: 重大利益</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Rather than fretting about joint exercises like those taking place this week, America should encourage China to participate in more of them, including the biennial multi-country RIMPAC manoeuvres, to be held off Hawaii next year. In May the Pentagon invited China to join in, for what would be the third time. Some American politicians grumble about the involvement of a navy so unfriendly to the West. But they are wrong to do so. Such exercises are an important way to prevent confrontation triggered by misunderstanding. And China’s inclusion would help ensure that its increasing naval assertiveness bolsters global security, rather than threatens it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>与其担心这周发生的联合演习， 美国应该鼓励中国更多地参与挤进来， 包括推迟到明年在夏威夷举行的多国RIMPAC军演。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>fret about</strong>: 担心某事</li>
<li><strong>biennial(adj.)</strong>: 两年一次的</li>
<li><strong>manoeuvre(n.)</strong>: 军事演习</li>
<li><strong>hold off</strong>: 推迟</li>
<li><strong>grumble about sth</strong>: 抱怨</li>
<li><strong>confrontation(n.)</strong>: 冲突，对抗，战役</li>
<li><strong>assertiveness(n.)</strong>: 坚定自信。 这里指表现的很自信，而且引人注目</li>
<li><strong>bolster global security</strong>: 巩固全球安全</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h1 id=&quot;The-new-gunboat-diplomacy&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#The-new-gunboat-diplomacy&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;The new gunboat diplomacy&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The new gun
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="English Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CoolDown 经济学人阅读(20) - Revive, don’t repeal</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2017/07/30/codetracer/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2017/07/30/codetracer/</id>
    <published>2017-07-29T17:03:44.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-29T17:06:23.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Revive-don’t-repeal"><a href="#Revive-don’t-repeal" class="headerlink" title="Revive, don’t repeal"></a>Revive, don’t repeal</h1><p>文章选自2017/7/22的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>导读: 美国医改继续不顺。 作者认为，不应该完全推翻奥巴马医保，而是应该重启他，并对其进行改革。 不能对其存在视而不见，也不能直接废除它。</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li><strong>revive(v.)</strong>: 复兴，振兴</li>
<li><strong>repeal(v.)</strong>: 废除</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>With health-care reform stalled, Republicans must now make the Affordable Care Act work</p>
</blockquote>
<p>随着医改停滞不前， 共和党必须立刻让平价医疗法案继续工作。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>stall(v.)</strong>: 拖延</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Only a madman would build America’s healthcare system from scratch. Its mix of private insurance, government-provided care and endless regulations is complicated, expensive and fails many vulnerable Americans. The Affordable Care Act, Barack Obama’s health-care law, is part of the mess. Yet those who passed it knew it was a grubby compromise. In America’s divided government, they reasoned, politicians must build on what already exists.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>只有疯子才会从头开始构建美国的医保系统。 这个融合了个人保险， 政府福利和无数管理条例的大杂烩十分复杂， 昂贵并且使许多弱势美国人感到失望。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>from scratch</strong>: 从头开始</li>
<li><strong>government-provided care</strong>: 政府提供的医疗</li>
<li><strong>fail(v.)</strong>: 使失望<br>e.g. He felt he had failed his family. 他感到辜负了家人</li>
<li><strong>Affordable Care Act</strong>: 美国的平价医疗法案</li>
<li><strong>a grubby compromise</strong>: 肮脏的妥协</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Following the travails this week of their latest attempts to “repeal and replace” Obamacare, Republicans must come to a similar realisation (see page 25). They are too divided to sweep away the status quo. Rand Paul, one of four senators who threatened to bring down the Senate bill, compared its continuation of parts of Obamacare to “German national socialism”. He wants to get government out of health markets. Susan Collins, another rebel, thinks the bill cuts Medicaid, government-provided health insurance for the poor, too deeply. These factions are unlikely to agree, however long the Republican leadership tries to find a compromise. One conservative gambit—to repeal Obamacare and worry about replacing it later—is a reckless gamble that would inflict crippling uncertainty on the health industry and those who rely on it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>在经历本周尝试”废除和替代”奥巴马医保的艰苦工作之后， 共和党内部必须达成共识。 他们分歧太大以至于难以理清现状。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>come to a realisation</strong>: 达成认识</li>
<li><strong>sweep away</strong>: 扫除，彻底消除</li>
<li><strong>status quo(n.)</strong>: 现状<br>e.g. restore the status quo 恢复现状</li>
<li><strong>bring down a bill</strong>: 推翻一个提案</li>
<li><strong>continuation(n.)</strong>: 续篇，延续</li>
<li><strong>Medicaid(n.)</strong>: 医疗救助制度</li>
<li><strong>conservative gambit</strong>: 保守的一招</li>
<li><strong>a reckless gamble</strong>: 不顾后果的赌博</li>
<li><strong>inflict crippling uncertainty</strong>: 带来严重的不确定性</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Get over the name<br>Republicans have long spoken as if Obamacare is a burning house; those inside must be rescued, even if it means taking an axe to the walls. But it is a fallacious argument designed to provide political cover to a Senate bill that is more about reducing redistribution than rescuing Obamacare’s customers from disaster (see page 26). The law’s problems are real, but fixable—more like a leaky roof and botched plumbing than a fire. The holes can still be patched up, in three steps.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>共和党长期以来将奥巴马医保比喻做一栋正在燃烧的房子； 必须从根本来治理， 尽管这意味要挥着斧子打碎墙壁。 但是这只是一个荒谬的政治幌子， 用于掩饰一个更多是减少再分配，而不是解救奥巴马医保客户走出灾难的议案。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>a fallacious argument</strong>: 充满谬误的理由</li>
<li><strong>political cover</strong>: 政治掩护</li>
<li><strong>botched plubing</strong>: 粗制滥造的管道系统</li>
<li><strong>patch up</strong>: 缝补</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>First, more states should emulate Alaska, Minnesota and Oregon, and start reinsurance programmes to pay the highest medical costs incurred on Obamacare’s insurance exchanges. Because the law forbids discrimination against those with pre-existing health conditions, the exchanges contain many sickly patients. As a result, premiums and deductibles have soared for the 9m buyers who earn too much to receive government subsidies. They foot much of the bill for Obamacare’s generosity. Meanwhile, 155m other Americans enjoy a tax break on the plans they get from their employers, which are often cheaper anyway. Reinsurance programmes would bring premiums down and begin to redress the imbalance. If it can get its act together, Congress could stump up some cash to help.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>首先， 更多的州需要效仿阿拉斯加，明尼苏达和俄勒冈，并开启分保保险计划来支付由奥巴马保险交易带来的费用。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>emulate(v.)</strong>: 仿效<br>e.g. Sons are traditionally expected to emulate their fathers. 历来认为儿子会仿效父亲</li>
<li><strong>reinsurance(n.)</strong>: 分保保险</li>
<li><strong>sickly patients</strong>: 多病的病人</li>
<li><strong>premiums and deductible</strong>: 保险费和免赔额</li>
<li><strong>tax break</strong>: 赋税减免</li>
<li><strong>redress the imbalance</strong>: 恢复平衡</li>
<li><strong>stump up</strong>: 掏腰包付钱<br>e.g. We were asked to stump up for the repairs. 人家要我们出修理费。</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Second, states should open government contracts for programmes like Medicaid only to insurers that take part in the exchanges. Those insurers are likely to apply because Medicaid is much larger than the market for individuals. Such rules, already in place in New York and Nevada, will help stem the flow of firms abandoning the exchanges, which has left a third of counties with only one insurer.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>第二，州应该开放一些项目的政府合同， 比如像医疗救助制度仅对参加交易的保险公司开放。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>insurer(n.)</strong>: 承保人，保险公司</li>
<li><strong>in place</strong>: 就位，投入使用</li>
<li><strong>stem the flow</strong>: 制止，遏制…的潮流。 强调阻止事情继续蔓延，发展，增加</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Finally, the Trump administration must fulfil the federal government’s responsibilities under Obamacare. That means enforcing its rules, such as a fine for those who choose not to buy health insurance. It also means paying the subsidies that underpin the system, something the president has been unwilling to do, thus deepening the problems on the exchanges. And it means seeking congressional approval for them to allay concerns that such payments are unconstitutional.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>最后， Trump的行政部门必须全面履行奥巴马医保中联邦政府的职责。 这意味着强制实施一些条例， 例如对那些不购买健康保险的家庭进行罚款。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>enforce rules</strong>: 强制实施法律/规定</li>
<li><strong>underpin the system</strong>: 巩固整个系统</li>
<li><strong>seek congressional approval</strong>: 征求国会的同意</li>
<li><strong>allay concerns</strong>: 缓解忧虑</li>
<li><strong>unconstitutional(adj.)</strong>: 违反宪法的</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Without a plausible replacement, killing off Obamacare, by repeal or by neglect, would be grossly irresponsible. Maddening as the system is, Republicans now have a responsibility to make it work.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>没有合理的方案， 通过废除或者无视来停止奥巴马医保， 将是极其不负责任的。 整个医疗系统如此狂怒， 共和党有责任让它有效。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>a plausible replacement</strong>: 貌似合理的替代方案</li>
<li><strong>kill off a project</strong>: 停止一个计划</li>
<li><strong>grossly irresponsible(adj.)</strong>: 极度地不负责任的</li>
<li><strong>maddening(adj.)</strong>: 令人发怒的</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h1 id=&quot;Revive-don’t-repeal&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Revive-don’t-repeal&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Revive, don’t repeal&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Revive, don’t repeal&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="English Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CoolDown 经济学人阅读(19) - Brain gains(2)</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2017/07/28/brain-gains-2/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2017/07/28/brain-gains-2/</id>
    <published>2017-07-27T23:22:10.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-27T23:22:57.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Brain-gains"><a href="#Brain-gains" class="headerlink" title="Brain gains"></a>Brain gains</h1><p>文章选自2017/7/22的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The other way edtech can aid learning is by making schools more productive. In California schools are using software to overhaul the conventional model. Instead of textbooks, pupils have “playlists”, which they use to access online lessons and take tests. The software assesses children’s progress, lightening teachers’ marking load and giving them insight on their pupils. Saved teachers’ time is allocated to other tasks, such as fostering pupils’ social skills or one-on-one tuition. A study in 2015 suggested that children in early adopters of this model score better in tests than their peers at other schools.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>另一种教育科技可以通过使学校教育更富有成效来帮助学习。 加州的学校正在试用软件对传统教育方式进行革新。 对于教科书， 学生们有‘playlists’来取代， 这个工具可以用来获取网课和进行测试。 软件将会评估学生的进步， 减轻教师的批卷负担并让教师可以深入观察学生的表现。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>overhaul(v.)</strong>: 全面革新</li>
<li><strong>give an insight on</strong>: 对…提出深刻见解</li>
<li><strong>foster social skills</strong>: 培养社交技能</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Pay attention at the back<br>Such innovation is welcome. But making the best of edtech means getting several things right. First, “personalised learning” must follow the evidence on how children learn. It must not be an excuse to revive pseudoscientific ideas such as “learning styles”: the theory that each child has a particular way of taking in information. Such nonsense leads to schemes like Brain Gym, an “educational kinesiology” programme once backed by the British government, which claimed that some pupils should stretch, bend and emit an “energy yawn” while doing their sums.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>这种创新很受欢迎。 但是做最好的教育科技意需要作对几件事情。 首先，个性化学习必须以学生的学习习惯为据。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>pseudoscientific ideas</strong>: 伪科学</li>
<li><strong>nonsense(n.)</strong>: 荒唐的事</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>A less consequential falsehood is that technology means children do not need to learn facts or learn from a teacher—instead they can just use Google. Some educationalists go further, arguing that facts get in the way of skills such as creativity and critical thinking. The opposite is true. A memory crammed with knowledge enables these talents. William Shakespeare was drilled in Latin phrases and grammatical rules and yet he penned a few decent plays. In 2015 a vast study of 1,200 education meta-analyses found that, of the 20 most effective ways of boosting learning, nearly all relied on the craft of a teacher.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>一个不那么重要的谎言就是科技意味着孩子们不需要学习事实或者从教师那里学习–他们可以使用谷歌来代替。 有些教育家更进一步， 认为事实会阻碍创造力和批判思维等技能的发展。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>falsehood(n.)</strong>:谎言</li>
<li><strong>get in the way of</strong>: 妨碍，阻碍</li>
<li><strong>cram with</strong>: 塞满…</li>
<li><strong>a vast study</strong>: 大范围的研究</li>
<li><strong>boost learning</strong>: 促进学习</li>
<li><strong>the craft of</strong>: …的手艺, 技艺</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>The second imperative is to make sure that edtech narrows, rather than widens, inequalities in education. Here there are grounds for optimism. Some of the pioneering schools are private ones in Silicon Valley. But many more are run by charter-school groups teaching mostly poor pupils, such as Rocketship and Achievement First—or Summit, where 99% of graduating pupils go on to university and laggards make the most progress relative to their peers in normal classes. A similar pattern can be observed outside America. In studies of edtech in India by J-PAL, a research group, the biggest beneficiaries are children using software to receive remedial education.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>第二个重要的事情就是需要确保教育科技在缩小教育的差距， 而不是使教育差距更大，更不平等。 有很多让人保持乐观的坚实基础。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>imperative(n.)</strong>: 极其重要的事情。 强调非常重要，必须要完成<br>e.g. The events of past few weeks make it imperative for her to act. 过去几周发生的事情使她不得不采取行动</li>
<li><strong>ground(n.)</strong>: 基础</li>
<li><strong>charter school</strong>: 特许公立学校</li>
<li><strong>laggard(n.)</strong>: 落后者</li>
<li><strong>remedial education</strong>: 补习班</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Third, the potential for edtech will be realised only if teachers embrace it. They are right to ask for evidence that products work. But scepticism should not turn into Luddism. A good model is São Paulo, where teachers have welcomed Geekie, an adaptive-software company, into public schools.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>第三， 只有当教师们支持它的时候， 教育科技的潜力才会被释放。 他们要求关于产品有效的证据是无可厚非的。 但是怀疑主义不应该转向勒德主义。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Luddism(n.)</strong>: 勒德主义，强烈反对提高自动化和机械化的程度。</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>In 1984 Skinner called opposition to technology the “shame” of education. Given what edtech promises today, closed-mindedness has no place in the classroom.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>1984年， Skinner称反对教育科技是教育界的耻辱。 鉴于教育科技今天的成功前景， 保守的思想在教室已无立足之地。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>promise(n.)</strong>: 成功前景</li>
<li><strong>closed-mindedness(n.)</strong>: 保守思想， 封闭思想</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h1 id=&quot;Brain-gains&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Brain-gains&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Brain gains&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Brain gains&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;文章选自2017/7/22的The Economist。 这里对文章
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="English Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CoolDown 经济学人阅读(18) - Brain gains(1)</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2017/07/24/brain-gains-1/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2017/07/24/brain-gains-1/</id>
    <published>2017-07-24T13:42:59.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-24T13:43:39.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Brain-gains"><a href="#Brain-gains" class="headerlink" title="Brain gains"></a>Brain gains</h1><p>文章选自2017/7/22的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>导读： 时至今日， 教育手段依旧没有质的飞跃， 即使一些IT，多媒体手段被应用到教学当中。 学生们依然无法真正享受到因材施教的最佳效果。 但是在最近， 马克.扎克伯格， 比尔.盖茨等科技大佬， 正在积极支持类似于Mindspark一类软件的发展， 力图为学生们提供量身定做的学习计划， 做到因材施教， 充分发挥学生的潜能。</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>脑力收益。 一些场景下， 也可以理解为人才引进</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Together, technology and teachers can revamp schools</p>
</blockquote>
<p>技术与教师可以一起改进学校</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>revamp(v.)</strong>: 改组，改进<br>e.g. revamp plans 修订计划</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>IN 1953 B.F. Skinner visited his daughter’s maths class. The Harvard psychologist found every pupil learning the same topic in the same way at the same speed. A few days later he built his first “teaching machine”, which let children tackle questions at their own pace. By the mid-1960s similar gizmos were being flogged by door-to-door salesmen. Within a few years, though, enthusiasm for them had fizzled out.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>在1953年， B.F.Skinner 参观了他女儿的数学课。 这个哈佛的心理学家发现所有的学生都在以相同的进度相同的方式学习相同的主题。 几天之后， 他制造了他的第一台教育机， 用来让学生们根据自己的进度来解决不同的问题。 但推广计划最终流产。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>tackle problem</strong>: 解决问题。 tackle 通常用于指解决难题</li>
<li><strong>at one’s own pace</strong>: 按照各自的进度</li>
<li><strong>gizmo(n.)</strong>: 小玩意儿，小装置</li>
<li><strong>flog(v.)</strong>: 出售，卖掉<br>e.g. They are trying to flog their house. 他们正试图卖掉房子。</li>
<li><strong>door-to-door salesman</strong>: 上门推销员</li>
<li><strong>fizzle out</strong>: 终成泡影， 虎头蛇尾， 最终失败<br>e.g. The game fizzled out in the second half. 比赛到了下半场叫人失望</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Since then education technology (edtech) has repeated the cycle of hype and flop, even as computers have reshaped almost every other part of life. One reason is the conservatism of teachers and their unions. But another is that the brain-stretching potential of edtech has remained unproven.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>自从那之后， 教育科技已经经历了重复的起起落落， 即使计算机已经几乎改变了生活的其他部分。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>edtech(n.)</strong>: 教育科技</li>
<li><strong>hype and flop</strong>: 炒作和失败, 起起落落</li>
<li><strong>unproven(adj.)</strong>: 未经证实的</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Today, however, Skinner’s heirs are forcing the sceptics to think again (see page 16). Backed by billionaire techies such as Mark Zuckerberg and Bill Gates, schools around the world are using new software to “personalise” learning. This could help hundreds of millions of children stuck in dismal classes—but only if edtech boosters can resist the temptation to revive harmful ideas about how children learn. To succeed, edtech must be at the service of teaching, not the other way around.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>时至今日， Skinner的后继者们正在迫使怀疑论者重新思索。 在科技巨富Mark Zuckerberg和Bill Gates的支持下， 世界上的一些学校正在使用新的软件来个性化学习。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>heir(n.)</strong>: 继承人</li>
<li><strong>billionaire techie</strong>: 家财万贯的科技迷</li>
<li><strong>dismal class</strong>: 沉闷的课堂</li>
<li><strong>edtech booster</strong>: 教育科技的支持者</li>
<li><strong>resist the temptation</strong>: 抵挡诱惑</li>
<li><strong>the other way around</strong>: 从相反的方向</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Pencils down<br>The conventional model of schooling emerged in Prussia in the 18th century. Alternatives have so far failed to teach as many children as efficiently. Classrooms, hierarchical year-groups, standardised curriculums and fixed timetables are still the norm for most of the world’s nearly 1.5bn schoolchildren.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>传统的教学模式在18世纪的普鲁士出现。 可替代方法远远不能有效地对大量的学生施教。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>standardised curriculums</strong>: 被标准化的课程</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Too many do not reach their potential. In poor countries only a quarter of secondary schoolchildren acquire at least a basic knowledge of maths, reading and science. Even in the mostly rich countries of the OECD about 30% of teenagers fail to reach proficiency in at least one of these subjects.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>很多人都不能发挥出他们的潜力。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>reach one’s potential</strong>: 发挥出潜力</li>
<li><strong>OECD</strong>: 经济合作与发展组织</li>
<li><strong>reach proficiency</strong>: 达到熟练的水平</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>That share has remained almost unchanged over the past 15 years, during which billions have been spent on IT in schools. By 2012 there was one computer for every two pupils in several rich countries. Australia had more computers than pupils. Handled poorly, devices can distract. A Portuguese study from 2010 found that schools with slow broadband and a ban on sites such as YouTube had better results than high-tech ones.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>那样的份额在过去的15年中始终保持不变， 在这些年中学校已经花费了数十亿的资金在IT建设上。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>handled poorly</strong>: 处理不当</li>
<li><strong>slow broadband</strong>: 慢网速</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>What matters is how edtech is used. One way it can help is through bespoke instruction. Ever since Philip II of Macedon hired Aristotle to prepare his son Alexander for Greatness, rich parents have paid for tutors. Reformers from São Paulo to Stockholm think that edtech can put individual attention within reach of all pupils. American schools are embracing the model most readily. A third of pupils are in a school district that has pledged to introduce “personalised, digital learning”. The methods of groups like Summit Public Schools, whose software was written for nothing by Facebook engineers, are being copied by hundreds of schools.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>重要的是教育科技如何被使用。 一种有效的方法就是采取因材施教的方法。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>bespoke instruction</strong>: 因材施教</li>
<li><strong>individual attention</strong>: 个体关照</li>
<li><strong>school district</strong>: 学区</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>In India, where about half of children leave primary school unable to read a simple text, the curriculum goes over many pupils’ heads. “Adaptive” software such as Mindspark can work out what a child knows and pose questions accordingly. A recent paper found that Indian children using Mindspark after school made some of the largest gains in maths and reading of any education study in poor countries.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>在印度， 有一半的孩子在离开小学之后不能阅读简单的文本， 课程被孩子们忘光。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>work out</strong>: 计算出</li>
<li><strong>pose questions</strong>: 提出问题</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h1 id=&quot;Brain-gains&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Brain-gains&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Brain gains&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Brain gains&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;文章选自2017/7/22的The Economist。 这里对文章
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="English Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CoolDown 经济学人阅读(17) - VR in La La land</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2017/07/23/lalaland/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2017/07/23/lalaland/</id>
    <published>2017-07-22T15:06:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-22T15:07:09.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="VR-in-La-La-land"><a href="#VR-in-La-La-land" class="headerlink" title="VR in La La land"></a>VR in La La land</h1><p>文章选自2017/7/08的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>导读: 虚拟现实技术日趋完善，日前在游戏市场，家用市场逐渐风行。 那么在电影领域又将会有何种作为呢？ 静待好莱坞的神奇。</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li><strong>La La land</strong>: 一语双关， 既指洛杉矶(LA)， 也指脱离现实的地方。<blockquote>
<p>Hollywood studios try out virtual reality</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
</ul>
<p>好莱坞电影制片公司正在试用虚拟现实技术</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>try out</strong>: 试用， 试验</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>OUTSIDE a squat grey building in Santa Monica, the California sun melts the tar. Inside, in a dark room roughly the size of a small shipping container, two men are exploring the world by means of virtual reality (VR). They squash spiders in an abandoned temple, hit a home run at Yankee Stadium and float through a Blade Runner-esque landscape, all in the span of eight minutes. It feels much longer than that, and also shorter—time is hard to grasp in VR.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>在Santa Monica的一所低矮的建筑外， 加州的太阳烧灼着柏油路面。在一个与集装箱差不多大小的黑暗小屋内， 两个人正在探索VR构建的世界。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>squat(adj.)</strong>: 低矮的</li>
<li><strong>tar(n.)</strong>: 焦油沥青<br>e.g. a tar road 柏油路</li>
<li><strong>shipping container</strong>: 海运集装箱</li>
<li><strong>hit a home run</strong>: 打出全垒打</li>
<li><strong>float through</strong>: 浮过</li>
<li><strong>in the span of</strong>: 在…的跨度上</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>The creator of the experience is Walter Parkes, a former boss of DreamWorks Pictures, a film studio, who last year co-founded Dreamscape Immersive. The startup plans a chain of VR multiplex cinemas offering ten-minute interactive experiences for around $15 each. The first will open at a shopping mall near Beverly Hills at the end of the year; another 14 are planned for 2018. Mr Parkes says it costs about $2m to make a ten-minute VR experience, compared with around $200m for a big-budget Hollywood movie (not counting marketing and distribution). The economics work even though people are entertained for much shorter periods, he argues.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Walter Parkes正是这种体验的创作者， 他是DreamWorks的前任老板， 去年联合创建了Dreamscape Immersive. 这个创业公司安排了一系列VR多厅电影院， 提供了价值15美元的10分钟的交互式体验。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>a film studio</strong>: 电影制片厂</li>
<li><strong>a chain of</strong>: 一系列的</li>
<li><strong>multiplex cinemas</strong>: 多厅电影院</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>The men and women over in Burbank, where the big studios are based, are interested. Dreamscape has attracted around $10m in investment from Fox, Warner Brothers and MGM, along with Steven Spielberg and Westfield, a shopping-centre operator. Disney has invested $66m in Jaunt, which makes tools for creating VR content. Warner Brothers recently announced a partnership with IMAX, which specialises in large-screen cinemas, to fund and create VR “experiences” for three upcoming films.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>遍布Burbank的男男女女都很感兴趣， 那座城市是很多大型电影制片厂的基地。 Dreamscape已经吸引了大概$10m的投资， 资方包括Fox, Warner Brothers 与 MGM, 连同斯皮尔伯格和大型购物广场运营商–Westfield。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>along with</strong>: 与…一起</li>
<li><strong>announce a partnership with</strong>: 宣布与…的合作关系</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Promotional and extra material for films in VR is the first priority. Later on studios expect VR to become a format of its own, a cross between movies and games. “The lines are getting blurred. They use a lot of the same tech, the same tools,” says Thomas Husson, an analyst at Forrester, a research firm.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>VR电影的宣传资料和额外资料会优先发放。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>promotional material</strong>: 促销资料</li>
<li><strong>first priority</strong>: 最优先的</li>
<li><strong>later on</strong>: 后来，稍后的</li>
<li><strong>get blurred</strong>: 变得模糊不清</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Hollywood is in a battle for attention as well as dollars. In the future Harry Potter fans, for example, may consider it a waste to go to an attraction in the English countryside when they can visit Diagon Alley at home in a headset. They may even do both. If studios get a grip of VR, every minute spent in a cinema could mean an extra one in a park and yet another in a headset.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>好莱坞正在一场吸引注意力和金钱的斗争中。 在将来， 当哈利波特的粉丝可以在家里通过头戴式设备访问Diagon Alley的时候， 他们也许会认为去英国乡村的名胜是浪费时间。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>headset(n.)</strong>: 头戴式受话器</li>
<li><strong>get a grip of</strong>: (完全)控制，支配</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h1 id=&quot;VR-in-La-La-land&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#VR-in-La-La-land&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;VR in La La land&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;VR in La La land&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;文章选自2017/7/08的
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="English Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CoolDown 经济学人阅读(16) - Containing Mr Kim</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2017/07/21/containing-mr-kim/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2017/07/21/containing-mr-kim/</id>
    <published>2017-07-21T12:26:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-21T12:26:54.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Containing-Mr-Kim"><a href="#Containing-Mr-Kim" class="headerlink" title="Containing Mr Kim"></a>Containing Mr Kim</h1><p>文章选自2017/7/08的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>导读：朝鲜已然拥有洲际导弹， 对周边国家， 尤其是大洋彼岸的美国， 构成了一定的威胁。 Trump也在积极努力，试图通过震慑的手段来限制金正恩不使用洲际导弹。 然而中国含糊其辞的态度，让事情并不顺利。</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>遏制金先生</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>America cannot stop North Korea from building long-range nuclear missiles. But it can deter it from using them.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>美国无法阻止朝鲜建造远程核弹。 但是可以威慑它不去使用</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>long-range nuclear missile</strong>: 远程核弹</li>
<li><strong>deter from</strong>: 防止。 带有威慑的含义</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>THE definition of an intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM) is one that can fly at least 5,500km (3,420 miles). The weapon that North Korea tested, with characteristic belligerence, on the Fourth of July, had a range of perhaps 6,700km (see page 21). So its claim to have built an ICBM is technically correct.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>洲际弹道导弹的标准之一就是可以飞行至少5，500km。 7月4日测试的导弹，大概可以飞行6,700km。 因此朝鲜确实有能力建造ICBM</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>intercontinental ballistic missile</strong>: 洲际弹道导弹</li>
<li><strong>belligerence(n.)</strong>: 好战性</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>That is not quite as alarming as it sounds. It allows Kim Jong Un, North Korea’s dictator, to threaten Anchorage, Alaska, as well as America’s bases on Guam and in Japan and South Korea. But Los Angeles and New York are still out of reach. More- over, North Korea has not yet mastered the technology to protect a nuclear warhead as a missile re-enters the atmosphere. And for the North to achieve much longer ranges it will have to add a third stage to its two-stage missiles—a further technological leap. Nonetheless, Mr Kim’s drive to develop a nuclear-tipped missile capable of striking America is clearly advancing rapidly. At best, America may have a few years before North Korea can rain destruction on its cities, as it so often threatens.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>这没有那么令人担忧。 导弹允许金正恩, 朝鲜独裁者， 威胁到Anchorage, Alaska， 还有美国在Guam的军事基地。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>alarming(adj.)</strong>: 令人担忧的， 使人惊慌的</li>
<li><strong>nuclear warhead</strong>: 核弹头</li>
<li><strong>technological leap</strong>: 技术跃变</li>
<li><strong>nuclear-tipped missile</strong>: 有核弹头的导弹</li>
<li><strong>at best</strong>: 最多</li>
<li><strong>rain destruction</strong>: 散布毁灭</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>It was not supposed to be this way. When Mr Kim boasted of being close to launching an ICBM, on New Year’s Day, Donald Trump retorted: “It won’t happen.” America tried to enlist China, North Korea’s main trading partner, to persuade Mr Kim to desist. For a few months China made encouraging noises about curbing the flow of goods across its border with the North. But Mr Trump’s growing friendship with Xi Jinping, his Chinese counterpart, seems to have cooled (see page 27). Mr Trump recently admitted that pressing China into service “has not worked out”. What else can he try?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>事情本不应该是这样的。 当金吹嘘近期要发射一枚导弹时，Trump反驳认为事情根本不会发生。 美国将谋求与中国合作来说服朝鲜。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>boast of</strong>: 吹嘘， 炫耀</li>
<li><strong>retort(v.)</strong>: 反驳</li>
<li><strong>enlist(v.)</strong>: 谋求/争取…的帮助</li>
<li><strong>desist(v.)</strong>: 停止， 不再做<br>e.g. The magazine will desist from such language after receiving complaints. 杂志接到投诉之后将杜绝使用此类语言。</li>
<li><strong>press into service</strong>: 临时任用， 暂时使用<br>e.g. The local bar has been pressed into service as a school. 当地酒吧被暂时用作学校</li>
<li><strong>work out</strong>: 有进展<br>e.g. Their marriage didn’t work out. 他们的婚姻不美满</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Despite lots of martial talk from Mr Trump, a pre-emptive strike against North Korea is a terrifying option. It would risk setting off a war on the Korean peninsula that could claim millions of lives. The less incendiary step of trying to shoot down Mr Kim’s missiles whenever he tests them would prevent the North from developing an ICBM. But America may not yet have perfected the anti-missile capabilities it needs.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>除了Trump的一堆武断的谈话, 先发制人打击朝鲜是一个可怕的选择。 这将冒着煽动朝鲜半岛争端的问题。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>a pre-emptive strike</strong>: 先发制人的袭击</li>
<li><strong>set off</strong>: 引发，触发</li>
<li><strong>an incendiary step</strong>: 具有煽动性的一步</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Mr Trump might resort to direct negotiations with North Korea—he once said that he and Mr Kim could settle all their differences over a burger at the White House. But it is hard to imagine that the North would really abandon its missile programme, which it appears to view as its one ironclad defence against a hostile world. Meanwhile, the confidence-building step that the North demands of America—suspending all military exercises with South Korea—should be a non-starter. The exercises are legal whereas the missile-testing is not. Also North Korea has a dire record of cheating on its commitments; suspension would perturb America’s allies; and China, which hates displays of American might on its borders, would have an incentive to keep Mr Kim as a near-nuclear threat.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Trump可能会诉诸于直接与朝鲜谈判-， 他认为他与金可以在白宫吃顿汉堡的功夫解决所有的分歧。 但是很难想象朝鲜会放弃导弹计划， 尤其是这已经成为它对敌对世界的有力防御。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>resort to</strong>: 诉诸于</li>
<li><strong>settle differences</strong>: 消除分歧</li>
<li><strong>ironclad defence</strong>: 牢不可破的防御</li>
<li><strong>military exercise</strong>: 军事演习</li>
<li><strong>non-starter(n.)</strong>: 不切实际的想法</li>
<li><strong>a dire record</strong>: 糟糕的纪录</li>
<li><strong>perturb(v.)</strong>: 使焦虑，不安<br>e.g. What perturbs me is that magazine articles are so much shorter nowadays. 让我不安的是现在的杂志文章都短多了</li>
<li><strong>a near-nuclear threat</strong>: 准核威胁</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Sanctions do make life difficult for the North Korean regime. But the only measure that might truly threaten it would be to cut its oil supply—and China has already declined to do that. America could punish more firms in China that abet trade with North Korea (secondary sanctions, in the jargon). But the border trade is too fluid and diffuse to halt the determined Mr Kim, who cares nothing for his people’s hardship.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>制裁固然会影响朝鲜的统治。 但是仅有的有效的制裁可能就是减少原油供应了–中国正在婉拒此事。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>sanction(n.)</strong>: 国际制裁</li>
<li><strong>fluid(adj.)</strong>: 易变的， 不稳定的</li>
<li><strong>hardship(n.)</strong>: 穷困</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>It helps if people believe what you say<br>For all of Mr Trump’s bluster, he has no good way of stopping North Korea from developing an effective nuclear weapon. Deterrence and containment remain the best (and possibly only) options to ensure that Mr Kim is never tempted to use his horrirying arsenal. But if deterrence is to be effective, America’s threats must be credible. So Mr Trump must stop making promises he is not ready or able to honour promises like stopping North Korea from developing an ICBM.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>在Trump的夸口中， 没有一个能阻止朝鲜发展核武器的好方法。 威慑与限制仍然是保证Kim不去使用那恐怖的武器的最好方法。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>bluster(n.)</strong>: 夸口</li>
<li><strong>deterrence and containment</strong>: 威慑与限制</li>
<li><strong>be tempted to do</strong>: 被引诱去做…</li>
<li><strong>honour promises</strong>: 履行承诺</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h1 id=&quot;Containing-Mr-Kim&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Containing-Mr-Kim&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Containing Mr Kim&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Containing Mr Kim&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;文章选自2017/7
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="English Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CoolDown 经济学人阅读(15) - The German problem(2)</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2017/07/21/the-german-problem2/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2017/07/21/the-german-problem2/</id>
    <published>2017-07-20T15:42:42.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-20T15:43:26.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>文章选自2017/7/08的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>But the adverse side-effects of the model are increasingly evident. It has left the German economy and global trade perilously unbalanced. Pay restraint means less domestic spending and fewer imports. Consumer spending has dropped to just 54% of GDP, compared with 69% in America and 65% in Britain. Exporters do not invest their windfall profits at home. And Germany is not alone; Sweden, Switzerland, Denmark and the Netherlands have been piling up big surpluses, too.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>但是这种模式的有害的副作用逐渐显现。 它导致德国经济与全球贸易处于危机一般的不均衡。 限薪意味着更少的国民消费与更少的进口。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>perilously(adv.)</strong>: 危机四伏地，充满危险地</li>
<li><strong>pay restraint</strong>: 限薪</li>
<li><strong>consumer spending</strong>: 消费性开支</li>
<li><strong>windfall profit</strong>: 意外利润，暴利</li>
<li><strong>pile up</strong>: 积累，堆放起来</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>For a large economy at full employment to run a current-account surplus in excess of 8% of GDP puts unreasonable strain on the global trading system. To offset such surpluses and sustain enough aggregate demand to keep people in work, the rest of the world must borrow and spend with equal abandon. In some countries, notably Italy, Greece and Spain, persistent deficits eventually led to crises. Their subsequent shift towards surplus came at a heavy cost. The enduring savings glut in northern Europe has made the adjustment needlessly painful. In the high-inflation 1970s and 1980s Germany’s penchant for high saving was a stabilising force. Now it is a drag on global growth and a target for protectionists such as Mr Trump.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>对于一个低失业率的大经济体， 超过GDP 8%的经常项目盈余会导致全球贸易体系经受严峻的考验。 为了补偿这些顺差和维持足够的需求来保证人们在工作， 其他国家必须借钱来维持。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>put a strain on</strong>: 使…经受严峻考验</li>
<li><strong>offset(v.)</strong>: 补偿， 抵消</li>
<li><strong>aggregate demand</strong>: [贸易]总需求</li>
<li><strong>with abandon</strong>: 放任，放纵</li>
<li><strong>notably(adv.)</strong>: 尤其<br>e.g. It is very popular, most notably among young girls. 这个非常受欢迎， 特别是在年轻女孩子中间。</li>
<li><strong>persistent deficits</strong>: 持续的赤字</li>
<li><strong>penchant(n.)</strong>: 爱好，嗜好，偏好</li>
<li><strong>savings glut</strong>: 存款过剩</li>
<li><strong>a drag on sth/sb</strong>: 对某物/某人是个累赘</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>The shift from thrift<br>Can the problem be fixed? Perhaps Germany’s bumper trade surplus will be eroded as China’s was, by a surge in wages. Unemployment is below 4% and the working-age population will shrink, despite strong immigration. After decades of decline, the cost of housing is rising, meaning that pay does not stretch as far as it used to. The institutions behind wage restraint are losing influence. The euro may surge. Yet the German instinct for caution is deeply rooted. Pay rose by just 2.3% last year, more slowly than in the previous two years. Left to adjust, the surplus might take many years to fall to a sensible level.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>如何修正这个问题？ 也许德国的巨大的贸易顺差可以通过增加工资来消除，正如中国做的那样。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>thrift(n.)</strong>: 节俭</li>
<li><strong>bumper(adj.)</strong>: 巨大的，大号的</li>
<li><strong>a surge in sth</strong>: 激增的<br>e.g. a surge in price</li>
<li><strong>instinct for caution</strong>: 谨慎的天性</li>
<li><strong>a sensible level</strong>: 合理水平</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>The government should help by spending more. Germany’s structural budget balance has gone from a deficit of over 3% of GDP in 2010 to a small surplus. Officials call this prudence but, given high private-sector savings, it is hard to defend. Germany has plenty of worthwhile projects to spend money on. Its school buildings and roads are crumbling, because of the squeeze on public investment required to meet its own misguided fiscal rules. The economy lags behind in its readiness for digitalisation, ranking 25th in the world in average download speeds. Greater provision of after-school care by the state would let more mothers work full-time, in an economy where women’s participation is low. Some say such expansion is impossible, because of full employment. Yet in a market economy, there is a tried and trusted way to bid for scarce resources: pay more.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>政府需要刺激消费。 德国的结构化预算余额已经从2010年占有超过3% GDP的赤字状态达到了现在的少量盈余。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>budget balance</strong>: 预算余额</li>
<li><strong>prudence(n.)</strong>: 审慎</li>
<li><strong>private sector</strong>: 私营部门</li>
<li><strong>defend(v.)</strong>: 为…做辩解</li>
<li><strong>worthwhile project</strong>: 有价值的项目</li>
<li><strong>crubling(adj.)</strong>: 逐渐破碎的，</li>
<li><strong>fiscal rule</strong>: 财政规则</li>
<li><strong>lag behind</strong>: 落后于…</li>
<li><strong>digitalisation(n.)</strong>: 数字化</li>
<li><strong>after-school(adj.)</strong>: 课外的</li>
<li><strong>bid(n.)</strong>: 争取<br>e.g. a bid for power 夺权的企图</li>
<li><strong>tried and trusted (adj.)</strong>: 经过考验的</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Above all, it is long past time for Germany to recognise that its excessive saving is a weakness. Mrs Merkel is absolutely right to proclaim the message of free trade. But she and her compatriots need to understand that Germany’s surpluses are themselves a threat to free trade’s legitimacy.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>总之， 德国很早之前就意识到了过度储蓄的危害。 Merkel发出自由贸易的倡导是绝对正确的。 但德国的顺差绝对是与自由贸易背道而驰的。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>compatriot(n.)</strong>: 同胞</li>
<li><strong>legitimacy(n.)</strong>: 合法性</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;文章选自2017/7/08的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the adverse side-effects of the model are increasingly
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="English Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CoolDown 经济学人阅读(14) - The German problem(1)</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2017/07/18/the-german-problem-1/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2017/07/18/the-german-problem-1/</id>
    <published>2017-07-18T11:40:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-18T11:41:20.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>文章选自2017/7/08的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>导读：Trump退出TPP, 在全球范围内积极奉行贸易保护主义， 企图以此来挽回国内的蓝领工作。 Merkel则反其道而行之，大肆鼓吹自由贸易。 Merkel貌似在做有利于国际贸易的事情，但实则不然，因为德国的贸易顺差竟然一直是世界第一位的。</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>德国问题</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Why Germany’s current-account surplus is bad for the world economy</p>
</blockquote>
<p>为什么德国的国际收支常项顺差对世界经济是有害的？</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>current-account surplus</strong>: 国际收支经常项目顺差</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>THE battle-lines are drawn. When the world’s big trading nations convene this week at a G20 summit in Hamburg, the stage is set for a clash between a protectionist America and a free-trading Germany.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>战线已然划定。 汉堡的G20峰会的舞台正是为坚守保护主义的美国与坚守自由贸易的德国而搭的。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>battle-lines</strong>: 战线</li>
<li><strong>a G20 summit</strong>: G20 峰会</li>
<li><strong>protectionist</strong>: 贸易保护主义的</li>
<li><strong>free-trading</strong>: 自由贸易的</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>President Donald Trump has already pulled out of one trade pact, the Trans-Pacific Partnership, and demanded the renegotiation of another, the North American Free-Trade Agreement. He is weighing whether to impose tariffs on steel imports into America, a move that would almost certainly provoke retaliation. The threat of a trade war has hung over the Trump presidency since January. In contrast, Angela Merkel, Germany’s chancellor and the summit’s host, will bang the drum for free trade. In a thinly veiled attack on Mr Trump,she delivered a speech on June 29th condemning the forces of protectionism and isolationism. An imminent free-trade deal between Japan and the European Union will add substance to her rhetoric (see page 62).</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Trump已经退出了TPP贸易协定， 并且正在重新磋商另外一个，北美自由贸易协定。 他正在权衡是否要对进口钢材征收关税， 这是一个几乎必定会激化矛盾的举措。 正相反， Merkel却在大肆鼓吹自由贸易，并在一次公开演讲中对Trump的举措含沙射影。 一个在日本与欧盟之间即将签订的自由贸易协定夯实了她的雄辩。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>pull out of</strong>: 退出<br>e.g. In reality, they will be arguing for Britain to pull out of the EU altogether. 实际上，他们将一起为英国退出欧盟做出辩护。</li>
<li><strong>trade pact</strong>: 贸易协定，条约</li>
<li><strong>impose tariffs on</strong>: 对…征收关税</li>
<li><strong>provoke retaliation</strong>: 挑起报复</li>
<li><strong>trade war</strong>: 贸易战</li>
<li><strong>bang the drum for</strong>: 公开表示对…的支持</li>
<li><strong>a thinly veiled attack</strong>: 含蓄的攻击<br>e.g. a thinly veiled allusion 含沙射影</li>
<li><strong>deliver a speech</strong>: 发表演讲</li>
<li><strong>add substance to</strong>: 为…增加内涵</li>
<li><strong>rhetoric(n.)</strong>: 雄辩，虚夸的言辞<br>e.g. an empty rhetoric of politicians 政客的大话空话</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>There is no question who has the better of this argument. Mr Trump’s doctrine that trade must be balanced to be fair is economically illiterate. His belief that tariffs will level the playing field is naive and dangerous: they would shrink prosperity for all. But in one respect, at least, Mr Trump has grasped an inconvenient truth. He has admonished Germany for its trade surplus, which stood at almost $300bn last year, the world’s largest (China’s hoard was a mere $200bn). His threatened solution—to put a stop to sales of German cars—may be self-defeating, but the fact is that Germany saves too much and spends too little. And the size and persistence of Germany’s savings hoard makes it an awkward defender of free trade.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>在这个问题上双方都没有绝对的说服力。 Trump坚信的均衡的贸易才是公平的信条是经济知识匮乏的表现。 他通过征收关税来创建公平贸易环境的想法既天真且危险，这可能影响整个市场的繁荣。 但是从另一方面来看， Trump已经抓住了让人感到为难的事实。 德国有世界最大的贸易顺差，甚至超过了中国。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>have the better of sth</strong>: 在…上更有说服力</li>
<li><strong>economically illiterate</strong>: 经济知识匮乏</li>
<li><strong>level the playing field</strong>: 创建公平的竞争环境</li>
<li><strong>shrink prosperity</strong>: 使繁荣缩水</li>
<li><strong>in one respect</strong>: 从一方面来看</li>
<li><strong>an inconvenient truth</strong>: 令人为难的事实</li>
<li><strong>admonish sb for sth</strong>: 就某事责备某人</li>
<li><strong>trade surplus</strong>: 贸易顺差</li>
<li><strong>stand at</strong>: 达到</li>
<li><strong>self-defeating(adj.)</strong>: 事与愿违的，弄巧成拙的</li>
<li><strong>an awkward defender</strong>: 尴尬的支持者</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Imperfect harmony<br>At bottom, a trade surplus is an excess of national saving over domestic investment. In Germany’s case, this is not the result of a mercantilist government policy, as some foreigners complain. Nor, as German officials often insist, does it reflect the urgent need for an ageing society to save more. The rate of household saving has been stable, if high, for years; the increase in national saving has come from firms and the government.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>实际上， 贸易顺差是一种相对于国民投资而言过剩的国民储蓄。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>at bottom</strong>: 实际上</li>
<li><strong>national saving</strong>: 国民储蓄</li>
<li><strong>domestic investment</strong>: 国内的投资</li>
<li><strong>mercantilist(adj.)</strong>: 重商主义的</li>
<li><strong>an aging society</strong>: 老龄化社会</li>
<li><strong>the urgent need</strong>: 迫切的需求</li>
<li><strong>household saving</strong>: 家庭储蓄</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Underlying Germany’s surplus is a decades-old accord between business and unions in favour of wage restraint to keep export industries competitive (see page 18). Such moderation served Germany’s export-led economy well through its post-war recovery and beyond. It is an instinct that helps explain Germany’s transformation since the late 1990s from Europe’s sick man to today’s muscle-bound champion.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>隐藏在德国的顺差背后的， 是几十年前企业与工会达成的协议——支持通过抑制工资增长来保证出口业的竞争力。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>in favour of</strong>: 支持，赞成</li>
<li><strong>wage restraint</strong>: 制止工资增长的决定</li>
<li><strong>moderation(n.)</strong>: 节制</li>
<li><strong>export-led economy</strong>: 出口导向经济</li>
<li><strong>post-war(n.)</strong>: 指二战后</li>
<li><strong>muscle-bound(adj.)</strong>: 肌肉强健的</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>There is much to envy in Germany’s model. Harmony between firms and workers has been one of the main reasons for the economy’s outperformance. Firms could invest free from the worry that unions would hold them to ransom. The state played its part by sponsoring a system of vocational training that is rightly admired. In America the prospects for men without college degrees have worsened along with a decline in manufacturing jobs—a cause of the economic nationalism espoused by Mr Trump. Germany has not entirely escaped this, but it has held on to more of the sorts of blue-collar jobs that America grieves for. This is one reason why the populist AfD party remains on the fringes of German politics.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>德国的模式令人嫉妒。 企业与工人之间的和谐关系已经成为经济发展出色的主要原因之一。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>outperformance(n.)</strong>: 业绩出色</li>
<li><strong>invest free</strong>: 自由投资</li>
<li><strong>union(n.)</strong>: 这里指工会</li>
<li><strong>hold sb to ransom</strong>: 绑架某人</li>
<li><strong>vocational training</strong>: 职业培训</li>
<li><strong>economic nationalism</strong>: 经济国家主义</li>
<li><strong>be espoused by</strong>: 被…拥护</li>
<li><strong>hold on to</strong>: 紧握</li>
<li><strong>grieve for</strong>: 为…伤心</li>
<li><strong>populist(adj.)</strong>: 民粹主义的</li>
<li><strong>on the fringes of</strong>: 在…的边缘</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;文章选自2017/7/08的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;导读：Trump退出TPP, 在全球范围内积极奉行贸易保护主义， 企图以此来挽回国内的蓝领工作。 Merkel则反其
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="English Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CoolDown 经济学人阅读(13) - Making things anew</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2017/07/16/makding-things-anew/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2017/07/16/makding-things-anew/</id>
    <published>2017-07-16T11:45:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-16T11:45:45.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>文章选自2017/7/1的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>导读: 英国的Domin公司正在尝试利用金属3D打印技术来生产通用的制造业部件。 金属3D打印的最大优势就是可以以更低廉的价格来制造更轻便的产品。 这是一个大胆的尝试。 3D打印技术的持续进步将来势必会对制造产生重大影响。</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li><strong>anew</strong>: (以不同的方式)重新，再一次。<br>e.g. She’s ready to start anew. 她准备重新开始。</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Printing in 3D transforms the economics of manufacturing</p>
</blockquote>
<p>3D打印正在改变制造业经济学</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>the economics of manufacturing</strong>: 制造业经济学</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Typically, a new manufacturing company begins by making small numbers of high-value items for niche markets before tooling up to produce stuff in large volumes for mass consumption. But Domin Fluid Power, a five-year-old firm based near Bristol, in England, has used 3D printing to go about things rather differently.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>通常情况下， 一个新的制造业公司在开始大规模生产前， 会在利基市场中生产少量的，高价值的商品来试水。 但是Domin Fluid Power， 一个在Bristol附近的5年的公司，使用3D打印技术从不同的截然不同的方向入手</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>niche market</strong>: 利基市场，在较大的细分市场中，具有相似兴趣的一小群顾客占有的市场空间。</li>
<li><strong>tool up</strong>: 给…配置设备</li>
<li><strong>mass consumption</strong>: 大规模消费</li>
<li><strong>go about</strong>: 着手做， 从事</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Domin began as a design service working in the aerospace industry, but after two years its bosses decided it should make its own products. Those they picked were high-performance hydraulic pumps and powered servovalves, both of which control fluids in mechanisms found in machines ranging from aircraft to processing plant in factories. The question was which market they should concentrate on.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Domin起家于做航空航天业的设计服务， 之后两年公司老板决定做自己的产品。 生产高性能液压泵和伺服操作阀。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>aerospace industry</strong>: 航空航天工业</li>
<li><strong>hydraulic pump</strong>: 液压泵</li>
<li><strong>powered servovalve</strong>: 伺服操作阀</li>
<li><strong>processing plant</strong>: 炼油厂</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Aerospace offers good profit margins. But it is a low-volume business and one in which new devices often take time to be accepted, delaying return on investment. The market for factory and general industrial equipment is broader, easier and quicker to enter, and can absorb large volumes. But it is price-sensitive. So, unless those volumes can actually be sold, and economies of scale achieved, bankruptcy looms. At least, it does with conventional manufacturing methods.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>航空航天提供了很棒的利润幅度。 但是这是一个小容量市场，并且一个新产品通常需要较长的时间被接受， 投资见效慢。 相反， 工厂和通用工业设备市场广泛， 容易快速进入， 并且能容纳大批量生产。但是却对价格十分敏感。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>profit margin</strong>: 利润幅度</li>
<li><strong>delaying return on sth</strong>:在…上延迟的收益</li>
<li><strong>price-sensitive</strong>: 对价钱敏感</li>
<li><strong>economies of scale</strong>: 规模经济</li>
<li><strong>bankruptcy looms.</strong>: 破产迫近。 loom 一般用于说明问题萦绕，挥之不去</li>
<li><strong>conventional manufacturing methods</strong>: 传统制造方法</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Domin, however, acquired a 3D metal printer from EOS, a German firm. And that, says Marcus Pont, the company’s general manager, overturned the calculations. For a start, economies of scale hardly matter with a 3D printer. Changing designs requires merely a tweak of the software, rather than the retooling of a factory. This means, at the operating level, the unit cost of making one thing or many things is about the same.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Domin从德国公司EOS购买了一台3D金属打印机。 根据Marcus Pont的计算， 首先， 大规模经济几乎与3D打印毫无关系。 对于3D打印，修改设计仅仅需要调整一下软件，而不是重新部署工厂。 这一位置， 在经营的层面上， 做一件事情的单位成本与做多件事情的单位成本是相近的。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>overturn the calculation</strong>: 推翻计算</li>
<li><strong>a tweak of the software</strong>: 对软件进行轻微调整</li>
<li><strong>the retooling of sth</strong>: 对…进行设备更新</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Moreover, a 3D printer can create sophisticated designs that require less material to make, which lets products be lighter. Usually, removing material from a product to lighten it makes it more expensive. Cutting, drilling and machining require extra work and thus incur extra cost. That would normally push a supplier into a market that values weight-saving (see table). At one end of the scale, Formula 1 motor racing, a kilogram saved may be the difference between winning and losing a race. In this business such a kilogram is worth more than $120,000. At the other end, saving a kilogram on equipment which sits on a factory floor is worth only a few dollars.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>此外， 3D打印可以制造用料更少， 更轻的精密的仪器。 通常情况下， 通过削减用料来减轻一台设备的重量会使其单价更贵。 削，钻和机器加工需要额外的工作， 因此引入额外的成本。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>sophisticated design</strong>: 精密的设计</li>
<li><strong>incur extra cost</strong>: 招来额外的花费。incur 一般指令人不快的事情</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>But with a 3D printer hardly any additional work is needed. Indeed, contrary to accepted wisdom, the lighter a part gets the cheaper it becomes to make, because of the materials saved. So Domin decided to enter the market for factory and general equipment first, with a competitively priced lightweight servovalve. This valve is, though, identical to the one they will offer for mobile hydraulics in tractors, diggers and trucks, and also to the one they hope will qualify for aerospace use. With a little modification, they think it will also crack the racing-car market, opening a way to reach the entire automotive industry.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>但3D打印几乎不需要任何额外的工序。 事实上， 与经验相反的是， 由于节省了材料， 一个部件越轻就越便宜。因此， Domin决定首先进军工厂和通用仪器。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>accepted wisdom</strong>: 公认的智慧</li>
<li><strong>enter a market</strong>: 进军一个市场</li>
<li><strong>general equipment</strong>: 通用设备</li>
<li><strong>qualify for</strong>: 具备资格，胜任</li>
<li><strong>crack the racing-car market</strong>: 拓展赛车市场</li>
<li><strong>the automotive industry</strong>: 汽车市场</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Mr Pont believes Domin is at the head of a trend. As 3D printers get faster and the quality of their output improves, the market for manufactured goods will, he reckons, change dramatically. “Industry needs to rethink the value of additive manufacturing,” he says. “It is not just a weight reducer but a cost reducer as far as we are concerned.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Pont认为Domin是潮流的引领者。 随着3D打印速度加快和产出品质量的提升， 制造业的市场将会产生巨变。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>at the head of</strong>: 在…的最前面</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;文章选自2017/7/1的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;导读: 英国的Domin公司正在尝试利用金属3D打印技术来生产通用的制造业部件。 金属3D打印的最大优势就是可以以更低
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="English Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CoolDown 经济学人阅读(12) - Printing things everywhere</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2017/07/14/printing-everywhere/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2017/07/14/printing-everywhere/</id>
    <published>2017-07-13T14:28:08.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-13T14:29:05.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>文章选自2017/7/1的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>导读：3D打印技术方兴未艾， 其构建原型产品的能力令人称道。 但是这项神器的技术是否能应用于大规模生产，进一步提高生产线的自动化？ 那就需要提升打印速度，降低物料成本。 Nike, Adidas, 匹克都推出了自己的3D打印鞋子，虽然售价较高，但是也证明了3D打印大规模生产的可行性。 3D打印在其他行业大显身手指日可待。</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li><strong>Printing things everywhere</strong>: 自由打印。 意在说明3D打印技术将会应用到制造业的各个角落</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>3D printers will shape the factory of the future</p>
</blockquote>
<p>3D打印将影响未来的工厂</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>shape(v.)</strong>: 影响…的发展<br>e.g. Like it or not, our families shape our lives and make us what we are. 无论喜欢与否，家庭影响了我们的生活， 决定了我们成为什么样的人。</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>MANUFACTURING advances often take time to catch on. Only later does their real significance become apparent. The flying shuttle, invented in 1733 by John Kay, a British weaver, allowed the production of wider pieces of cloth. Because its movement could be mechanised, the shuttle later became one of the innovations which paved the way for the Industrial Revolution. In 1913 Henry Ford brought motoring to the masses by making his Model T on a moving assembly line; but it was Ransom Olds, a decade earlier, who had come up with the idea of an assembly line to boost production of the Olds Curved Dash. Throughout the 1980s factory bosses scratched their heads over Taiichi Ohno’s Toyota Production System and its curious methods, such as the just-in-time delivery of parts. Now it is the global benchmark for factory efficiency.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>制造业的改进总需要些时间来普及。 直到后来他们的重要性变得明显的那一刻。 例如推动工业革命的飞梭技术， 福特的可移动装配线，丰田的生产系统。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>manufacturing advance</strong>: 制造业发展</li>
<li><strong>catch on</strong>: 流行起来</li>
<li><strong>flying shuttle</strong>: 飞梭（一种纺织工具）</li>
<li><strong>pave the way for</strong>: 为…铺平道路</li>
<li><strong>the Industrial Revolution</strong>: 工业革命</li>
<li><strong>assembly line</strong>: 装配线</li>
<li><strong>scratch one’s head</strong>: 苦思冥想</li>
<li><strong>global benchmark</strong>: 全球标杆</li>
<li><strong>just-in-time delivery</strong>: 实时派送</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>What, then, to make of the potential of Chuck Hull’s invention in 1983 of “stereolithography”? Mr Hull is the co-founder of 3D Systems, one of a growing number of firms that produce what have become known as 3D printers. These machines allow a product to be designed on a computer screen and then “printed” as a solid object by building up successive layers of material. Stereolithography is among dozens of approaches to 3D printing (also known as additive manufacturing).</p>
</blockquote>
<p>如何看待Chuck Hull在1983年发明的‘立体光刻技术’的前景？ 这个技术是3D打印的实现方法之一</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>make of</strong>: 理解，看待</li>
<li><strong>stereolithography</strong>: 立体光刻技术</li>
<li><strong>additive manufacturing</strong>: 增材制造</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Printing has become a popular way of producing one-off prototypes, because changes are more easily and cheaply made by tweaking a 3D printer’s software than by resetting lots of tools in a factory. That means the technology is ideal for low-volume production, such as turning out craft items like jewellery, or for customising products, such as prosthetics. Dental crowns and hearing-aid buds are already being made by the million with 3D printers. Because it deposits material only where it is needed, the technology is also good at making lightweight and complex shapes for high-value products ranging from aircraft to racing cars. GE has spent $1.5bn on the technology to make parts for jet engines, among other things.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>打印技术已经成为了一种生产一次性原型的流行手段，因为改动产品时，只需要调整3D打印的软件，而不用重新设置工厂里的工具， 更加方便和廉价。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>one-off prototype</strong>: 一次性原型</li>
<li><strong>tweak the software</strong>: 稍微调整软件</li>
<li><strong>low-volume production</strong>: 小批量试产</li>
<li><strong>turn out</strong>: 生产，制造<br>e.g. They have been turning out great blades for 400 years. 他们生产优质刀片已经有400年历史了</li>
<li><strong>prosthetic(n.)</strong>: 假肢</li>
<li><strong>dental crown</strong>: 牙冠</li>
<li><strong>hearing-aid bud</strong>: 助听器</li>
<li><strong>by the milliion</strong>: 数以百万的</li>
<li><strong>jet engine</strong>: 喷气式发动机</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>But sceptics still rule the roost when it comes to goods made in high volumes. They say that 3D printers are too slow and too expensive—it can take two days to create a complex object. Unlike the techniques pioneered by Kay, Olds and Ohno, additive manufacturing will never revolutionise mass production. Such scepticism looks less and less credible.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>但是怀疑者仍然坚信它不适合大规模生产。 他们认为3D打印又慢又贵</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>rule the roost</strong>: 主宰一切</li>
<li><strong>come to</strong>: 谈到，达到</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Some of the new methods of 3D printing now emerging show that its shortcomings can be overcome (see page 17). Adidas, for one, has started to use a remarkable form of it called “digital light synthesis” to produce the soles of trainers, pulling them fully formed from a vat of liquid polymer. The technique will be used in a couple of new and highly automated factories in Germany and America to bring 1m pairs of shoes annually to market much more quickly than by conventional processes. A new technique called bound-metal deposition has the potential to change the economics of metal printing, too, by building objects at a rate of 500 cubic inches an hour, compared with 1-2 cubic inches an hour using a typical laser-based metal printer.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>一些新兴的3D打印技术显示其缺点可以被克服。 Adidas已经使用3D打印生产运动鞋底。</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>the soles of trainers</strong>: 运动鞋的鞋底</li>
<li><strong>a vat of</strong>: 一大桶</li>
<li><strong>liquid polymer</strong>: 液体聚合物</li>
<li><strong>automated factory</strong>: 自动化工厂</li>
<li><strong>conventional process</strong>: 传统工艺</li>
<li><strong>metal printing</strong>: 金属印刷</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Layers of meaning<br>As in previous manufacturing revolutions, factories will take time to be transformed. The dexterity of human hands still beats the efforts to introduce the fully automated production of clothing, for example. But automation is spreading to every production line in every country, and 3D printing is part of that trend. As wages in China rise, some of its mass-production lines are being fitted not just with robots but the first 3D printers, too. And as global supply chains shorten, bosses will want to use additive manufacturing to tailor products to the demands of local consumers. The full consequences of the technology’s spread are hard to predict. But when they do become clear, Mr Hull’s name may well be bracketed with the likes of Kay, Olds and Ohno.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>正如之前的制造业革命， 工厂需要时间来转型。 灵巧的双手仍会在一些行业完胜自动化生产， 例如衣服生产。 但是自动化已经深入到每个国家的每一条生产线</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>dexterity(n.)</strong>: (双手的)灵巧， (思维的)敏捷</li>
<li><strong>introduce the fully automated production</strong>: 采用全自动生产</li>
<li><strong>mass-production lines</strong>: 大规模生产线</li>
<li><strong>fit(v.)</strong>: 安装，安置</li>
<li><strong>supply chain</strong>:供应链</li>
<li><strong>the technology’s spread</strong>: 技术传播</li>
<li><strong>bracket sb with…</strong>: 把…与…相提并论</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;文章选自2017/7/1的The Economist。 这里对文章进行生词释义和句子分析，仅供学习使用，欢迎交流。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;导读：3D打印技术方兴未艾， 其构建原型产品的能力令人称道。 但是这项神器的技术是否能应用于大规模生产，进一步提高生产
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="English Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/English-Learning/"/>
    
    
      <category term="The Economist" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/The-Economist/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
